what I would love to do is call someone
我最想做的就是周五把人叫到
to my office on Friday I love firing
办公室来。我喜欢
people on Friday
周五炒掉别人。
now my next guest is one of the biggest
我的下一位嘉宾是
names in real estate a successful
房地产界的大腕，一位成功的
entrepreneur and star of a hit TV show
企业家，也是一档热门电视节目的明星。
now the female Titan is getting some
这位女强人现在有点
heat the minute or woman cries you're
招人恨，女人一哭你就等于拱手让人。
giving away your power Harvard is
哈佛
definitely Over the Top If I wasn't
绝对是顶尖的。如果我没有
dyslexic and I didn't have a hard time
阅读障碍，学习上没有那么辛苦，
in school I don't think I would have
我想我不会
been successful I think I had 22 jobs
成功。在创业之前，我大概换了22份工作。
person I meet is in real estate in New
我在纽约遇到的每个人都在做房地产，
York so how did you become the best I
那么你是怎么成为最棒的呢？我当时在
was competing with the old boys network
和那些老男孩俱乐部竞争，
and they were asleep at the wheel nobody
他们根本没意识到问题所在，没人
was thinking of new ideas in real estate
想到房地产领域的新点子。
I would think of the greatest [__]
我会想出各种天花乱坠的谎言
to create publicity did I manipulate
来制造话题。我操纵
them I played my cards everything I've
他们了吗？我出牌了。我一生所做的一切都是为了向
attempt to show the world that I'm not
世界证明我并不
stupid Ramon Simone he was my boyfriend
傻。拉蒙·西蒙当时是我的男朋友，
at the time and he offered to loan me a
他提出借给我
thousand dollars to start a business
一千美元和
with him he was my 51 business partner
他一起创业。他是我的第51个商业伙伴。在
seventh year we were in business yeah he
我们合作的第七年，她和我的秘书私奔了。 在生意上，他
said you'll never succeed without me you
说没有我你永远不会成功。你
know insults can really be a wonderful
知道吗，侮辱其实可以成为一种绝佳的
motivator I knew I was going to succeed
动力。我知道我会成功，
I had to just because I had to show him
我必须成功，因为我必须证明
that he was wrong if you're driven by
他错了。如果你被
these unhealthy insecurities you need to
这些不健康的焦虑所驱使，你需要
go and see a shrink I'm afraid to see a
去看心理医生。我害怕去看心理
shrink why why well you'd ask good
医生，为什么？为什么？因为你会问一些好
questions damn you
问题。该死的，我
I had an issue I felt
感觉……在
before this episode starts I have a
这一集开始之前，我遇到了一些问题。我有
small favor to ask from you two months
个小忙想请你帮。两个月
ago 74 of people that watch this channel
前，我们频道74%的观众
didn't subscribe we're now down to 69 my
没有订阅，现在只有69个了。我的
goal is 50 so if you've ever liked any
目标是50个。所以，如果你喜欢
of the videos we've posted if you like
我们发布的任何视频，如果你喜欢
this channel can you do me a quick favor
这个频道，能不能帮我个忙，
and hit the Subscribe button it helps
点击订阅按钮？这对
this channel more than you know and the
频道的帮助比你想象的要大得多。
bigger the channel gets as you've seen
正如你所看到的，频道越
the bigger the guests get thank you and
壮大，我们邀请的嘉宾也就越多。谢谢，祝你收听
enjoy this episode
愉快。
[Music]
（音乐）
we always start this conversation in the
我们
same place on this podcast because it's
在这个播客里总是从同一个地方开始讨论，因为
earliest context of Our Lives seems to
我们生活的最初背景似乎无可避免地
shape us in a way that then changes the
塑造了我们。 这种方式不仅改变了
trajectory of who we are but also molds
我们的人生轨迹，也塑造了
our character and really like hones our
我们的性格，真正磨砺了我们的
motivation so my question for you to
动力。所以我想问你的
start is what is that context from your
是，从你幼年
earliest years that I need to understand
时期开始，我需要了解哪些背景才能更好地
to understand you
了解你？
first off I'd say competition I I was
首先，我想说的是竞争。我是
one of 10 children we of course only had
十个孩子中的一个，我们只有
two parents to share uh we're in very
父母两个人，我们住在非常
tight quarters of two bedroom and just
狭小的两居室里，想要
to get the attention of a parent
引起父母的注意都
was very hard to do
非常困难。
so I think everyone in my family
所以我认为我的家人，
certainly myself grew up very
当然也包括我自己，都成长在一个竞争激烈的环境中，渴望得到
competitive competitive for attention uh
关注，渴望
competitive to do something better than
比别人做得更好。
the next kid
随之
and what also came with it we grew up in
而来的是，我们从小就生活在
a team so we never knew what it was like
团队中，所以我们从未体会过
to be alone my idea of doing anything is
孤独的滋味。我做任何事的想法都是：
who's with me who's with me and I think
谁和我一起？谁和我一起？我想
we all I shouldn't speak to everyone in
我们所有人都是如此。我不应该把
my family but I'll speak just for myself
我家里的每个人都说出来，但我可以只说说我自己。
now I think I'm phenomenal at building a
我认为我非常擅长组建
team but it's second nature to me it was
团队，这对我来说就像是本能一样。我
so easy for me to think of who would go
很容易就能想到谁应该和谁一起行动，谁
with who who wouldn't go with who who
不应该和谁一起行动，谁能相处融洽，谁负责什么
would get along who had the right task I
任务。我只
could just size somebody up really fast
需要…… 我能很快看透一个人，
and make a great tight team and I don't
并组建一个非常紧密的团队。我
think that would have happened if I
想，如果我
didn't grow up in a very crowded
不是在一个非常拥挤的
household looking for more attention and
家庭长大，渴望获得更多关注，并且不断
competing
竞争，我就不会拥有这种
the ability to suss people out and
能力。
understand them you're saying that came
你说这种洞察力和理解他人的能力
from having nine siblings
源于我有九个兄弟姐妹，
I certainly think it did yeah because
我当然这么认为。因为在
you have a crowded household so you know
一个拥挤的家庭里，你会看到各种各样的人际关系，所以你知道
who the leaders are on what category you
谁是哪个领域的领导者，你
know who's going to squeal to the
知道谁会向
parents you know who's going to shut up
父母告状，谁会闭嘴，
you know who can do your work for you
你知道谁能在
when you don't want to do it yourself
你不想做的时候帮你做事，
you know who you know who you could know
你知道谁可以帮你，你知道你能从谁那里得到什么，你知道
you get you develop all the talents to
你能培养哪些才能，从而把
get life in a form that you want it in
生活变成你想要的样子。18
years old with a lot of skills that
岁离开家庭时，你已经拥有了很多
other kids really haven't had the
其他孩子没有
opportunity to do
机会获得的技能。那么，你的
influence of your mother and father
父母对你的影响呢？
oh and I was thank God I had a mother
哦，我很感谢上帝，我的
and father who loved us
父母爱我们。
um I think that's the most important
我认为这是
gift in life it makes you somewhere deep
人生中最宝贵的礼物，它让你内心深处感到
inside secure if you feel loved and I
安全。 我感受到了爱，我的
had two parents who loved me you know
父母都非常爱我。
um my mother was a phenomenal role model
我的母亲是一位了不起的榜样，
I never saw her sleep she worked 24 7.
我从未见过她睡觉，她一天24小时、一周7天都在工作。
she just never sat down I don't know
她几乎从不坐下来，我甚至不知道
even when she slept I've never seen her
她什么时候睡觉，我这辈子都没见过她
go to bed ever in my life and my father
上床睡觉。我的父亲
worked two jobs his whole life to
一生都在打两份工来
support us so we were very much
养家糊口，所以我们深受
influenced by each parent as needing to
父母的影响，他们让我们明白努力
work hard I mean we were all having jobs
工作的重要性。我的意思是，
when we were 11 years old I think I had
我们11岁的时候就开始工作了，在
22 jobs before I started my own business
我自己创业之前，我大概做过22份工作，
because we were out working to
因为我们都在外面工作，
contribute to the family and think about
为家庭做贡献。想想看，
household when you're working young I
年轻时在家庭之外工作能学到多少生活技能？我
don't think anybody ever has any job
想没有人会在任何一份工作中
where they didn't learn something about
不学到一些东西。
themselves so even though when I went
所以，即使我
business at 23 I may have looked 23 but
23岁开始创业，进入职场时看起来只有23岁，但
inside I felt like I was 53 based on
内心却感觉自己像53岁一样成熟，因为我积累了丰富的
experience and so there was nothing
经验。所以，
naive about me at that point I had had
那时的我并不天真，我已经拥有了非常丰富的
already an awful lot of experience
阅历。
when I was reading through your story I
当我读到你的故事时，我了解到
I read that your father struggled with
你的父亲在
work and struggled with I think having a
工作中遇到了困难。 我觉得他很不适应有
boss he certainly did and he set up the
老板，他确实很不适应，而且他为
pattern that we all shared in my family
我们全家树立了榜样：
nine out of the ten kids have their own
十个孩子里有九个都自己
business my father was a printing press
创业。我父亲以前是印刷厂的
foreman and a very good worker but he
工头，工作能力很强，但他
didn't like someone telling him what to
不喜欢别人对他指手画脚，
do so he would regularly come home sit
所以他经常回家坐在餐桌旁
at the dinner table and tell us he was
告诉我们他被
fired from his job it was a regular
解雇了。这几乎成了家常便饭。
event we all asked her and tell us a
我们都会问他，让他讲个
story and it was the same story he would
故事，而他讲的故事总是千篇一律。基本上，他会
he said I I told Mrs Stein where to
说：“我让斯坦太太把那份
shove the job where the sun don't shine
工作扔到天涯海角去，
that was my and we'd all clap for him
那是我的！”然后我们都会为他鼓掌，
and say Dad our hero and my mother of
说：“爸爸，我们的英雄！”当然，我妈妈当时肯定很担心，
going to be fit until he found a new job
直到他找到新工作，我们该怎么办。
but he was a hero and so when we grew up
但他确实是我们的英雄。所以，当我们长大后，
even though he never worked for himself
尽管他从未自己创业，但
the fact of the matter is is we knew we
事实上，我们知道自己
wanted to work for ourselves we didn't
想为自己工作，不想
want to work for a boss and honestly I
为老板打工。老实说，我从来没有
never had a boss I liked even though I
喜欢过哪个老板，尽管我
had so many and I'm sure they're
有很多老板，我相信他们都是
perfectly fine people but I didn't like
很好的人，但我就是不喜欢
the fact that I wasn't the boss it was
那种感觉。 我不是老大，这一点
clear to me he um your father drunk
对我来说很清楚。嗯，你父亲
drank sometimes yes he did drink
有时候会喝酒，是的，他确实会喝酒。嗯，
I'll tell you how that played a role in
我会告诉你这在
our family he was a social drinker so he
我们家是如何影响的。他是个社交型饮酒者，所以他
was probably the best father in the
可能是世界上最好的父亲，和
world played with us was our Playmate
我们一起玩耍，是我们的玩伴，
our we adored him everything he did but
我们崇拜他的一切。但是，
then when we went out to a party which
当我们出去参加聚会时（这种情况
wasn't that often a family party he
并不多，主要是家庭聚会），他会
would drink too much and he would come
喝得太多，回来后就
back and he was a different person he
判若两人，像只
was a gorilla and we all feared him what
大猩猩，我们都害怕他。这会导致什么呢？嗯，
of control when you with a parent who
当你的父母
drinks I think as a child you never
喝酒时，你会非常渴望掌控一切。我想，作为孩子，你永远不会
really feel like you're in control of
真正觉得自己能掌控
things because you don't know when the
事情，因为你不知道什么时候“
lion might come out and so it made us
狮子”会变出来。所以这让我们缺乏
insecure and very fond of control and
安全感，非常渴望掌控一切。
I'm a control freak I like to control
我就是个控制狂，我喜欢掌控
everything I do and I credit my dad with
我做的一切，这要归功于我的父亲。
that I don't want any curveballs or
我不希望有任何意外或
surprises the way that he spoke to a
突发情况。从
throughout your story and the person you
你的故事和你后来的为人来看，他有时对母亲说话的方式似乎…… 这
consequential to how you did respond to
对你如何回应那些
talk down to you in your career God you
在职业生涯中贬低你的男人有着相当大的影响。天哪，你
do your research good for you really
做了这么多研究，真为你高兴。这确实
that's a Nuance but
是一个微妙之处。
um
嗯，
I'm not my best if a man talks down to
如果一个男人贬低我，我就不会发挥出最佳状态。这要
I'll credit my father with that because
归咎于我的父亲，因为
I adored my mother so much there was
我非常爱我的母亲，没有什么可以
nothing to talk down to my mother about
贬低她的东西。
but when he was drinking he would talk
但他喝醉后就会
down to my mother
贬低我的母亲，
and I hated him for it
我为此恨他，这种
and it scars you so deeply
伤害如此深刻，我永远也无法
that I'll never get rid of that so if a
摆脱。所以，如果一个
man actually dismisses me or talks down
男人真的轻视我或贬低
for me particularly in business
我，尤其是在商业领域，
I'm at my best it's like Oh no you're
我会全力以赴，就像“哦不，你
not going there I get like this iron Rod
不能这么做！”一样。
through my soul
我的灵魂仿佛被一根铁棍刺穿。向
showing someone uh that they're wrong is
别人证明他们错了，这
probably not the best motivation I gotta
可能不是最好的激励方式，我
believe probably not a healthy way to be
认为这可能不是一种健康的方式，
and you probably need a shrink on that
你可能需要去看心理医生。
one but it certainly works well in
但这在
business I think it pushes you it makes
商业领域确实很有效，我认为它能激励你，确保
sure that you make sure that things work
事情顺利进行。
I really resonate with that because as
我对此深有同感，因为正如
I've talked about probably too much on
我在
this podcast my my mother and father had
这个播客中可能谈到太多次的那样，我的父母关系
a very
非常……
loud way to communicate to say the least
大声说话，至少可以说，这真是一种很
what a lovely way of putting it I've
响亮的沟通方式。你这说法真够委婉的。我
with Harry frame that but yeah a loud
跟哈里说话越来越委婉了，不过，没错，大声说话确实是一种
way of communicating and I I learned
沟通方式。我小时候看着
watched my mother shouting at my dad
妈妈冲爸爸大吼大叫，就学会了这种方式。
when I got older my response to being
长大后，我对被
shouted at was the response I always
吼的反应，正是我一直
wish I'd seen in my dad oh which was
希望爸爸能有的反应——那就是
like run and don't take it ah so when
跑，别忍气吞声。所以，
you were saying that I was wondering if
你刚才说这个，我就在想，
you could relate in the sense of when a
你是否也有过类似的经历，当一个
man puts you down because you saw your
男人贬低你的时候，因为你亲眼目睹了
mother be put down in such a way your
妈妈被贬低，你的
response is to
反应是不是每次都是
every time brace up yeah and most
振作起来，最
importantly uh prove his assessment of
重要的是，证明他对
me wrong
我的评价是错的？
did your mother how did she respond
你妈妈是怎么回应的？
uh I have to actually think I think my
嗯，我得好好想想，我觉得我
mother was so busy
妈妈当时忙着
making sure my father
确保爸爸
was safe to his children
对孩子们的安全，
that I think she was just making sure we
所以她总是在确保我们
were safe all the time in those
安全。
instances you know and it's kind of
你知道，这有点
crazy you know you figure it out I mean
不可思议，你知道吗？
the next morning my dad would wake up
第二天早上，我爸爸醒来，
and he was the most popular guy in the
他就是街坊邻里最受欢迎的人，
neighborhood taking every kid in the
带着
neighborhood out Baseball playing
街坊邻居的孩子们去打棒球。 他
teaching them how to play tennis he did
教孩子们打网球，
he was everybody's favorite father and
他是大家最喜欢的父亲，就在前一天
only the night before my mother was
晚上，我妈妈还把
hiding us you know so it was kind of a
我们藏起来，你知道吗？所以这有点奇怪，
odd Dynamic she was hiding you well
她把我们藏起来，
hiding us because she didn't want my
因为她不想让我
father to have his Wrath
父亲的怒火发泄
on any of his children you know
到任何一个孩子身上，你知道吗？
so she was protecting us so kind of
所以她保护我们，把
separating us out yeah
我们隔离开来。是的，
wrath it's a strong word
怒火，这是一个很重的词，
wrath is a strong word uh I mean wrath
怒火是一个很重的词。我的意思是，怒火，
is it could be you know just angry words
你知道，愤怒的话语
can be so damaging uh
会造成很大的伤害。
you know nah whatever it's weird you're
你知道，算了，你让
making me feel sad I guess you're
我感到难过，这很奇怪。我想你应该让我难过，对吧？
but it's so sad you know it's so sad uh
但这太令人难过了，你知道，这太令人难过了。
addiction
成瘾，
because it brings out the very worst in
因为它会激发
an individual
一个人身上最糟糕的一面，
and the traits my dad had a wonderful
以及我父亲的那些特质。我的父亲是一位很棒的父亲，在我
father growing up just wonderful we
成长过程中，他真的很棒，我们再也
couldn't hope for a better father
找不到比他更好的父亲了。
um that he was so good that he forgave
他太好了，以至于我原谅了他过去的
him for the bad you really did as a kid
坏事。小时候，你真的会原谅他，
because it's oh good dad's back oh good
因为你会想：“哦，好爸爸回来了，哦，好
dad's back but again I said too early I
爸爸回来了。”但我又说了，太早了。我
think it leaves the scars of insecurity
认为这会在不安全感的伤痕中留下印记。
with children because you don't know if
孩子们，因为你不知
door when the door opens like who are we
道门打开时会遇到什么，比如“我们会
going to get now you know so it keeps
遇到谁？”你知道，所以
when we think about addiction we we see
当我们想到成瘾时，我们会感到紧张不安，我们把
it as like a manifestation of pain yes
它看作是痛苦的一种表现，是的，
or like it is of sorts was that is that
或者说某种程度上是这样。这和
relevant to what you observed in your
你观察到的你
father no I think with my father it was
父亲的情况有关吗？不，我认为我父亲的情况
honestly uh entirely due uh to too much
完全是由于
pressure on one man
一个人承受了太多的压力。
think about it he worked two jobs he
想想看，他同时做两份工作，
washed trucks every night through the
每天晚上都去洗卡车，
night because he could wash them fast
因为他洗得快，可以
and sleep a little then he'd go to his
睡一会儿，然后
day job at the morning he had three
早上再去上班。
children by the time he was 23 he had
他23岁时已经有了三个孩子，
seven children by the time he was 30.
30岁时已经有了七个孩子。
and he was a Workman and he was
他是一名工人，他要
supporting us uh trying to make us happy
养活我们，努力让我们快乐，
trying to share his time with us as best
尽他
he could which he really did a great job
所能地陪伴我们，他在这方面做得非常出色。
um I think it was just too much pressure
我认为
for a young man uh of what he signed up
对于一个年轻人来说，他所承担的压力太大了。
for I think it was hard I mean it wasn't
我认为这很艰难，我的意思是，
ever assured with us as children that we
作为孩子，我们从来没有得到过任何保证，我们是否
would necessarily get groceries
一定会……
you know so and he felt ashamed of that
你知道，他当时负责买菜，为此感到羞愧，觉得
like he should be the provider but it
自己应该承担起养家的责任。但这并
didn't stop him from quitting the job
没有阻止他在
the next week
下周
when the boss told him what to do so
老板让他辞职后就辞职。所以，
it's really a shame my dad didn't have
我爸爸没能拥有
his own business I think he would have
自己的事业真是太可惜了。我觉得他如果拥有自己的
been phenomenal in his own business all
事业，一定会非常成功。
of his kids did except for one and
他的孩子除了一个以外都创业了，而且
they're all hugely successful so I feel
他们都非常成功。所以我觉得
like he just didn't have the
他只是没有足够的
affordability of starting his own
经济能力去
business you know what role did the lack
创业。你知道吗，
of money in your household have on
家里缺钱对你
shaping your view on money
金钱观的形成有什么影响？
interesting enough very little really
很有意思的是，影响很小。
what was great about my mother is she
我妈妈最棒的地方就是她
never worried about money now here's a
从不为钱发愁。现在想想，她
money and my dad should have worried
和爸爸都应该
about money but I remember when I had
为钱发愁，但我记得
thought I'd be going out of business at
我创业的很多次都差点破产，
the 11th hour I tried everything didn't
我尝试了各种方法，觉得再也撑不下去了。
month and I remember in one of those
我记得在一段非常
dark times my mother called him she said
艰难的时期，我妈妈打电话给他，说：“
you sound distracted I said well
你听起来心不在焉。”我说：“说
honestly mom I think I'm going out of
实话，妈妈，我觉得……” 我当时正准备关门
business and on Monday sales meeting I'm
大吉，周一的销售会议上，我正在
actually writing a speech to say goodbye
准备一份告别演讲稿，表达
and how thankful I am and she said don't
我的感激之情。她却说别
worry about money it's an awful waste of
担心钱，那纯粹是浪费
time and you know I stopped worrying
时间。你知道吗，她
about money when she said it I thought
说完这句话之后，我就不再为钱操心了。我突然想到
of a new idea and it kept us in business
一个新点子，让我们又维持了
another two months my mother's attitude
两个月的生意。我母亲
toward money was it was meant to be
对金钱的态度是，钱就是用来
spent
花的。
uh you know as a kid I guess I would
你知道，小时候，我肯定更
have liked to have a new coat versus get
想要一件新外套，而不是穿别人穿过的旧衣服。
my hand-me-downs you know that's always
你知道，对
better for a girl to feel like she looks
一个女孩来说，让自己看起来漂亮总是更好的。
pretty okay uh but you know we were we
但是，你知道，我们一家人都很快乐，
were pretty much a happy bunch and so
所以
money didn't weigh in so far as you're
金钱并不是衡量幸福的标准。
happy and also my parents never measured
而且，我的父母从来不用
anyone by money they never had a comment
金钱来衡量任何人，他们从来不会评论
about who's rich who's not rich who has
谁有钱谁没钱，谁拥有
what it was just not even on their radar
什么，这些根本不在他们的考虑范围之内。
so it was really about my mother's
所以，真正重要的是我母亲的
Mantra supported by my father when he
信条，我父亲在他身体健康的时候也支持这个信条：
was fine was kindness how kind can you
善良。你能
be to the neighbor what could you do for
对邻居多好？你能为
the lady down the street and we all were
街坊邻居做些什么？我们都是这样被教育
raised on that and as a result of it we
长大的。 结果就是，
even though we didn't have more money to
即使我们没有更多钱，我们也能从帮助别人中获得满足感，
help out just doing nice things for
只是尽力做好事，
people and so money was not really on
所以钱真的不在我们的考虑范围内。
the radar honest to God yeah what about
老实说，对吧？学校怎么样？
school how is oh School sucked
哦，学校糟透了，
school is tough on kids that can't learn
对那些学不会的孩子来说太难了。
I was one of those kids you know myself
我就是其中之一，你知道吗？我
and my two brothers the other kids were
和我的两个兄弟，还有其他
eight students but we just couldn't read
八个孩子，我们就是不会读不会
we couldn't write we couldn't learn and
写，学不会。在
in a school situation is you judge
学校里，一个孩子会
yourself based on school grades what
根据成绩来评判自己。除此之外，
else do you have you someone could say
你还能有什么呢？有人可能会说
she's such a nice girl well that might
她是个好女孩，这
sound good but if you're getting all F's
听起来不错，但如果你全是F，
you feel terrible you just feel terrible
你会感觉糟透了，真的糟透了。
and so
所以，
um your sense of self I think is formed
我认为你的自我认知
very much by how good a student you are
很大程度上取决于你
in all school systems and it shouldn't
在所有教育体系中的学习成绩，这不应该，
be because it's just one kind of
因为这只是其中一种
intelligence of course but it is that
智力，但事实就是如此。
way when you're a student you sum
当你还是个学生时，你会
yourself up based on whether you could
根据自己能否
get good grades or not that's as simple
取得好成绩来总结自己，就这么简单。
were you bullied in school no not at all
你在学校被欺负过吗？没有。
I was too quiet to be bullied you know I
我根本就没被欺负过，你知道，我太安静了，根本不可能被欺负。我
was quiet and lovely and that's what the
安静又可爱，仁爱修女会的
Sisters of Charity always told my
修女们总是这样跟我
parents she's not very smart but she's
父母说：“她不太聪明，但
quiet and she's lovely quiet and lovely
她安静又可爱。”
I heard her my whole life and I was I
我从小就听她们这么说，但我从来
never said a word because I didn't have
没说过一句话，因为我没有
the confidence to say a word I wasn't
自信，我不想
going to speak up and be found out and
开口说话，怕被人发现。
uh those aren't the kids that were
呃，那些孩子并不是被
bullied the reason I asked about the the
欺负的那种人。我问你关于
question about being bullied is because
被欺负的问题，是因为
I I know that you're dyslexic and often
我知道你有阅读障碍，
especially in in that day and age we
尤其是在那个年代，我们对阅读
didn't understand dyslexia so we just
障碍了解甚少，所以我们
thought those kids were
觉得那些孩子都是被欺负的。
yeah did you ever feel
你有没有感受到过
that kind of criticism from your peers
来自同龄人或老师的那种批评？
from the teachers yes I had one teacher
老师说的有，我
in third grade that really gave me a
三年级的时候有个老师给我贴了一个
label that stuck with me till I got out
标签，这个标签一直伴随着我，直到我
of high school
高中毕业。
she said to me if you don't learn to
她对我说：“如果你不学会
read you'll always be stupid and she
阅读，你永远都是个笨蛋。”她
said the word stupid with such disdain
说“笨蛋”这个词的时候充满了鄙夷，
that was the first time I really heard
那是我第一次真正听到
that word before that no one told me I
这个词，在那之前没有人跟我说过。 我当时觉得
was stupid
很蠢，我肯定有问题，
it's wrong with me I'm stupid
我太蠢了。就在那时，
and that's when I got quiet that's when
我突然安静下来，从此
I just shut up and never talked again in
闭口不言，再也没在
school because I didn't want to be
学校说过话，因为我不想
called on to
被叫去
read out loud I mean for me my idea of
朗读。对我来说，人间
Hell on Earth was being told to read out
地狱就是被叫去朗读，
to read those days you go up and down
那时候学认字的方式就是在过道里来回走动，轮到谁就读谁 ...
you know what I think in hindsight if I
事后看来，如果我
wasn't dyslexic and I didn't have a hard
没有阅读障碍，如果我
time in school I don't think I would
在学校没有遇到困难，我想我不会
have been successful believe it or not
成功，信不信由你。
because I think everything I've done in
因为我觉得我人生中所做的一切都是为了向
show the world that I'm not stupid so
世界证明我并不笨。所以
I'm driven because I'm always there's a
我动力十足，因为我内心深处总有一个声音在怀疑自己是否
not be smart I mean I know it's bizarre
聪明。我知道这很奇怪，
because I'm smart but in an insecure
因为我其实很聪明，但在缺乏安全感的
situation I doubt myself sometimes but
情况下，我有时会怀疑自己。但
I've learned to replace the tape I don't
我已经学会了替换掉那些负面的声音。我的
have sister Stella Maria in my head
脑海里不再有斯特拉·玛丽亚姐姐的声音
anymore telling me I'm stupid I have a
告诉我我很笨，现在我听到的是属于我
tape of my own telling me I'm incredible
自己的声音，它告诉我我很棒，
I'm beautiful boy you could do this this
我很漂亮，孩子，你能做到，这没什么
is nothing you know I've got that tape
大不了的。你知道，这些
that I had to replace over the years but
年来我一直在替换那些负面的声音，但我要
let me tell you it took me a lot of
告诉你，我花了很长时间，很多很多
years a lot of years to now I can't say
年才做到现在这样。我不能说
I totally replace it but mostly put a
我已经完全替换掉了它，但基本上已经彻底消除了它。
to get over the Damage Done if your
如果你的
self-perception is a negative worn from
自我认知是负面的，那么要克服它造成的伤害需要付出巨大的努力。 一
the get-go because we all don't leave
开始，因为我们都无法
our childhoods behind so readily they
轻易摆脱童年的阴影，
stay with us I think
我认为它们会一直伴随着我们。
and you you credit it there for your
你肯定也把这种阴影归功于你的
drive
动力，
absolutely but also you said
但你之前也说过，
earlier if you're driven by these kind
如果你被这种
of unhealthy insecurities you need to at
不健康的焦虑所驱使，你迟早需要去看心理医生。
some point go and see a shrink I'm
我
afraid to see issuing why I'm afraid
害怕去看心理医生，因为害怕
they'll straighten me out and would I be
他们会把我“矫正”好，然后我是否真的会
successful then
成功？如果是这样，我会
I stay a mile away I know it's crazy
离他们远远的。我知道这很疯狂，
I've read a few books and self-analyze
我读过一些书，也做过自我分析，
but no no no first of all they're very
但是不行不行不行。首先，
expensive in New York and then that way
纽约的心理医生收费很高，而且
I'm too cheap to pay
我太抠门了，付不起。我的心理医生会告诉我，
my shrink is working out if I work out
如果我锻炼
or if I weed my garden I'm straightened
或者给花园除草，我
out for the moment okay but
暂时就能“矫正”自己。好吧，就是
that's the way it is I ask for selfish
这样。我问这个问题是出于自私的
reasons I found myself at one point for
原因。我曾经也因为
the same sort of insecurities and
同样的焦虑而
feeling like I wasn't enough being very
感到自卑，觉得自己不够好，
driven to like prove the world that I
一心想向世界证明自己。但这种动力在某种程度上是以牺牲
cost of like this other set of things
其他一些
which are important for happiness
对幸福、
relationships and balance and whatever
人际关系、平衡等等都很重要的东西为代价的。
else so when you said about someone you
所以，当你 你说你
need to go see a shrink I get it because
需要去看心理医生，我明白，因为
at some point you can be a bit too
有时候你会被证明
pursuit to prove the world that you are
自己
enough that you of course it's too much
足够优秀的执念所拖累，当然，这会导致很多
compromise a bunch of other things of
妥协，很多其他方面也会受到影响。我的
course you do I mean if you're strong
意思是，如果你很强大，总得有所取舍。为了
relaxing I don't think I've ever relaxed
放松，你不得不做出什么牺牲？我想我这辈子都没真正放松过。
in my life uh but honestly when I'm
但说实话，当我
relaxed uh reading a book it's fine for
放松的时候，比如读半个小时的书，感觉还不错，
and then I gotta get up and accomplish
但之后我就得起身去做
something I'm very driven to accomplish
一些我非常想做的事情，
to see the difference I've made in the
看看我给这个
world to an individual I just spoke to
世界带来了什么改变——无论是对刚刚交谈过的人，还是我
to a business I've been involved in uh
参与过的企业，亦或是我
to a neighbor I've befriended I've got a
结交的邻居。
I've got us why because I want to know
我有很多想法，为什么？因为我想确信
for sure without a doubt that I haven't
无疑地知道，我没有
wasted a minute and that my existence
浪费一分一秒。 我的存在意义重大，
makes a difference why
为什么？
because I I think it's important why
因为我认为这很重要。为什么？
well you ask good questions damn you why
你问得好，该死的，为什么？呃，
uh why is that because I don't want it
为什么？因为我不想
to be a wasted life you know I'm just
虚度此生。你知道，我就是那种只有
one of those that you one shot at it and
一次机会的人，
I want to see how much of an influence
我想看看我能产生多大的影响，
and how much of a difference I can make
能带来多大的改变。
I really do I mean so I guess relaxing
真的，我想。所以，我觉得放松就像是在
feels like wasting time it doesn't mean
浪费时间。但这并不意味着
that I can't have fun with friends I
我不能和朋友们一起玩。我
have the most
有
a great circle of close friends that I
一群很棒的好朋友，和他们在一起非常
have so much fun with that's a priority
开心。这在
in my life and it was a priority in my
我的生活中很重要，在我的事业中也很重要。在
developing teams I believe but
团队建设中，乐趣是最重要的。但是，
um in addition to that I just uh I just
除此之外，我
have to be productive I do need a shrink
必须保持高效。我需要一个心理医生，对吧？
don't I do you have one in the house
你家就有一个，
they give me a courtesy hour
他们可以免费给我一个小时。
okay I'm trying to get a discount
好吧，我想打个折。
um off you went into the world of work
你进入职场后，
as you said you had some by the way you
正如你所说，你有一些工作经验。顺便说一句，你
would make a good shrink can we just
会成为一个很棒的心理医生。我们
switch gears
换个话题吧？
you don't realize what's happening here
你没有意识到这里发生了什么。
I'm actually using you as my shrink
实际上，我把你当成了我的心理咨询师，
that's really I don't think so now I ask
这真的……我不这么认为。我现在问的
questions that I genuinely care about so
问题都是我真正关心的，
and typically that means because I'm
通常这意味着我遇到了
struggling with something so so that's
一些困难，所以才会如此
diligently
努力地探索这条路。
um you had some 22 or 23 jobs before you
嗯，在你创业之前，你做过大约22或23份工作。
started your own business yes I did jobs
是的，我做过
from everything from being a
各种各样的工作，从
receptionist to a waitress to everything
接待员到服务员，应有尽有。
we often look back at those jobs that
我们经常会回顾那些
didn't pay us a lot and that the world
收入不高、
doesn't hold in high regard as some
不被世人重视的工作，有些
people might think that they are a waste
人可能会觉得这些工作是在浪费
of time or they were like necessary
时间，或者觉得它们毫无必要。
what's your view on the when you're a
你如何看待你做
receptionist and a waitress how what
接待员和服务员的经历？这些经历
role did that play in your overall
在你的整体成功中扮演了什么角色？
success I think whether you have a
我认为，无论你从事的是
menial job or an important job it's what
卑微的工作还是重要的工作，重要的是
you're learning I mean there wasn't a
你学到了什么。我的意思是，没有哪份
job where I didn't learn a lot for me I
工作让我学不到东西。对我来说，我
would take any job not based on pay but
会接受任何工作，不是因为薪水，而是因为
gee what could I learn what could I
我能学到什么？我能
learn because that made you more
学到什么？因为这会让你更
valuable I never really thought it made
有价值。我从来不认为
you more valuable to be paid more but
薪水高低会让你更有价值。 但是，
hey I haven't done this before let's see
嘿，我以前没做过这个，让我们看看
what this is about and you learn skills
这是怎么回事。你会学到很多技能。
I think I learned more through my
我觉得我从当
waitressing jobs I always had a few at
服务员的工作中学到的东西更多。我总是同时做好几份工作，
once you know you could always get a
你知道，你总能找到一份
waitress job behind a counter I think I
柜台后面的服务员工作。我觉得我从当服务员那里
learned more about people waitressing
学到的关于人际交往的知识比创业还要多。
than building my business honest God you
老实说，
good today you've learned how to hustle
你得了解顾客，你的地盘就是你的柜台，你得让他们满意，你想稍微推销一下，比如你可以说，你知道第二杯咖啡免费，但要不要来一块芝士蛋糕？今天真的很好吃。你学会了如何努力工作，学会了
you learn how to be organized how to get
如何有条理，如何把
the containers in order how to make sure
容器摆放整齐，如何确保
they're filled when the customer steps
顾客离开时容器是满的，
out how to get that person something to
如何在
drink while you're working on this
服务这位
person I mean I learned so much in every
顾客的同时给下一位顾客提供饮料。我的意思是，我在每
one of those jobs and you know what's
一份工作中都学到了很多。你知道同时做
great about having a lot of jobs you
很多工作的好处是什么吗？你会
start to get a profile of what you're
开始了解自己
good at and what you're not and I in
擅长什么，不擅长什么。
short order after maybe seven or eight
很快，大概做了七八份
jobs not that I knew what I was going to
工作之后，虽然我不知道自己以后
do for a living but I knew what I was
要做什么，但我 虽然生活拮据，但我知道自己
good at I knew I was good at getting
擅长什么。我知道自己擅长
along with people and making them smile
与人相处，能让他们开心。
I could talk to somebody and make them
我可以和人交谈，让他们感到
happy absolutely and I also knew that I
快乐，绝对没问题。我也知道自己
was efficient I could create a system in
效率很高，我可以把任何事情都整理成系统。如果
anything I would see at the diner
看到餐馆
counter all wrong not running right I
柜台上出现问题，运转不畅，我
would talk to the boss say you know if
会和老板沟通，比如，如果
you did this with the maple syrup and
枫糖浆的配方和
changed sugar and I could like an
糖的用量都调整一下，我就可以像个
executive I could rearrange the whole
高管一样，高效地重新布置整个
counters you know in an efficient manner
柜台。
and I started learning that those were
我开始意识到，
my two gifts people and efficiency and
人际交往和效率就是我的两大天赋。
if you think about any business those
想想看，对于任何企业来说，这些都是至关重要的因素。
are really big ticket items if you could
如果你能
choose people motivate people get along
选择人，激励员工，
with people make them get along with
与员工和睦相处，让他们
each other plus create systems to grow a
彼此和睦相处，再加上建立系统来发展
big business I mean the minute you have
壮大企业，那就太好了。我的意思是，一旦你的员工
more than a half dozen people you need
超过六个人，你就需要
systems and my companies are always so
系统。我的公司总是
well organized that it they ran like
组织得井井有条，
they just ran like a Swiss clock is that
运转得就像瑞士钟一样精准。这个
a good analogy everything was in its
比喻恰当吗？一切都井然有序，
place nothing had to be duplicated it
无需重复劳动，一切都
was fast forward and so I was able to
快速推进。因此，我能够迅速
build very quickly which I had to do
发展壮大，而我必须这样做，
because we had big people in my market
因为我的市场里有很多大公司。
and if I had built and replicated
如果我建立并复制…… 如果按
systems at a normal Pace I would never
正常速度，我永远也
catch up to them so I had to do double
追不上他们，所以我必须加倍甚至
triple time and what's your answer on
三倍的时间。你觉得呢？
that one systems systems get you moving
系统能让你不断
forward get you get get a business like
前进，让你像
a machine you know and that was a gift I
机器一样运转，你知道吗？这是我
got from my menial jobs thank God I
从那些卑微的工作中获得的馈赠。感谢上帝，我
worked imagine if I hadn't worked and
工作过。想象一下，如果我没工作，就贸然进入
went out into the real world thinking I
社会，觉得自己
was dumb that I couldn't do anything
很笨，什么都做不了，
just because I couldn't read or write
仅仅因为我不识字。
thank God I learned could be a lifeguard
感谢上帝，我学会了如何做救生员，如何做
I learned I could be a tent salesman I
帐篷推销员，
could be Barbara buttons calling for
如何像芭芭拉·巴顿那样
solicitations eight hours a day I could
每天打电话推销八小时，如何做
be all those menial jobs hot dog
所有这些卑微的工作，比如
salesman sell more hot dogs in the next
卖热狗，比别人卖得多。
guy I mean I had Confidence from every
我的意思是，每
one of those jobs like look how cool I
一份工作都让我充满自信，就像在说“看我多酷！”
am maybe I wouldn't win Respect by
也许我不会赢得
everybody well who cares about the hot
所有人的尊重，谁在乎
dogs but in my book I knew I sold more
热狗呢？但在我看来，我知道我卖的
hot dogs than he sold on his you know so
热狗比他卖得多。
so no thank God for the jobs you learned
所以，感谢上帝，感谢那些工作，
so much by trying different jobs on you
通过尝试不同的工作，我学到了很多东西。你
know it's so important at that age if
知道，在那个年纪，这非常重要。如果
I'd asked you what you wanted what your
我问你想要什么，你会说什么？ 你的
dream was what would you have answered I
梦想是什么？你会怎么回答？我
wouldn't have answered the question I
不会回答这个问题，我
had no idea I would say I just want to
我会说我只想
work I just want to quote work it didn't
工作，我只想工作，做什么工作都
make a difference what I was working at
无所谓，
I just knew that when I was working I
我只知道工作的时候我
felt capable that's all and conversely
觉得自己有能力，仅此而已。反过来，
then what are you bad at I think as
你不擅长什么？我觉得就像
you've said it's very important to know
你说的，了解自己的
strengths but also weaknesses you know
优势和劣势都很重要。你知道
what I'm bad at a bad at math numbers
我什么不擅长吗？数学很差，数字很糟糕，
just terrible really I don't even
真的非常糟糕，我甚至都不懂。
understand I took algebra four times
我代数学了四次，
four times two years in summer school
暑期学校上了两年，
never passed it they finally just gave
都没通过。最后他们只是给了
me the grade to go through
我及格分。
um I'm very bad at math I'm bad at legal
嗯，我数学很差，法律很差，
I'm bad at committee meetings
委员会会议很差，
I'm bad at listening to a blow heart who
听不进长篇大论的人说话很差，他们只会喋喋不休，
just goes on and on doesn't cut to the
不切实际。我
chase I'm very bad at impatience I want
非常没耐心，我想
to know what you want from me and then
知道你想要我做什么，然后
you tell me how you got there I don't
你告诉我你是怎么想到的。我不
want to hear how you got there and then
想听你先说你是怎么想到的，然后再问
what do you want I always want to cut to
你想要什么。我总是想直接切入正题。
the chase so I'm impatient I've learned
追逐的过程让我很没耐心，我学会了
to hide it because you can't be so
掩饰，因为你不能
visibly impatient with people but as
对别人表现出明显的不耐烦。但
long as they tell me what they want on
只要他们一开始就告诉我他们想要什么，
the front end I could hang in there for
我就可以耐心听完他们
the long explanation after because I've
之后冗长的解释，因为我已经想好了要做
already concluded what I'm going to do
什么。
you know yeah so that's what I'm bad at
你知道，这就是我的弱项。
but lucky for me I've always surrounded
幸运的是，我身边总是围绕着
myself with people who are opposite to
与我截然相反的人。
me you know and by the way I shouldn't
顺便说一句，我不应该
really say I'm bad at numbers because I
说自己不擅长数字，因为我
had a business partner in my 10 business
有一个商业伙伴，
partner Esther my whole life I made her
埃丝特，我一辈子都是她的
my partner she was great at legal and
合伙人。她精通法律和
finance and she has to spent hours when
财务，每次
we wanted to open one or two new offices
我们想开一两家新办公室的时候，她都要花好几个小时计算，
doing the numbers to see if we could
看看我们是否
afford it and I used to come into our
负担得起。我以前常常走进
office and say what do you think she
办公室问她：“你觉得怎么样？”她
says I don't think we should really do
说：“我觉得我们不应该
it I said well let me tell you why we're
这么做。”我说：“那让我告诉你为什么我们要
going to do it because you really need
这么做，因为你们真的需要
to beat the next guy and let me tell you
击败竞争对手。我告诉你，
if we have eighty thousand dollars and
如果我们有八万美元，而
the desk produces only 40 42 it's going
部门只算出了40、42，那……”
to take us about nine months to actually
我们大概需要九个月才能真正
meet our overhead and we'll have to cut
收回成本，而且我们还得
back on the advertising we'll have the
削减广告预算，让
managers work for free
经理们免费工作。
and she'd say what and it worked every
她会说“什么”，而且每次都奏效，
time so I must have had a
所以我肯定对
taste for numbers in that kind of a way
数字有那种感觉。
I could always see the picture on
我总能从数字中看出端倪，
numbers and I'd be right it was bugged
而且我总是对的。这让
the crap out of her because she had all
她非常恼火，因为她掌握着所有
the numbers you know but
数据，你知道吗？但是，嗯，是的，
um yeah but I'm not good at adding up
我根本不擅长算数。
the numbers at all a lot of people think
很多人觉得，
I think it's really liberating to hear
听到他们说自己不擅长算数，我觉得很轻松。
that they probably exclude themselves
他们可能因为不擅长算数而从心理上把自己排除在
mentally of being a business person
经商之外。
because they are bad at numbers oh gosh
天哪，
I think numbers are the least important
我认为数字在商业中是最不重要的。
thing in business by far I look at all
看看我
the entrepreneurs I've invested in Shark
在《创智赢家》（Shark Tank）节目中投资的所有创业者，
Tank I am telling you
我告诉你，
the most successful I hope I'm not
最成功的那些——我希望我没有
giving anybody the short haul here but
低估任何人——他们
the most successful are not good at
并不擅长
numbers they're exceptional at people I
算数，他们非常擅长人际交往。我
think if you're great at people and you
认为，如果你擅长人际交往，并且
have ambition you have the two magic
有抱负，你就拥有了在商业上成功的两张魔法
cards
牌。这就是关键所在：
what it's about people and ambition the
人际交往和抱负。
drive to get to the Finish Line yeah
努力到达终点线，
then you find a way you hire the people
然后你就会想办法，雇佣你
you need you borrow the people you need
需要的人，借用你需要的人，用你的天赋
you exchange your gift for their gift
交换他们的天赋，
part-time if you have to get what you
如果需要的话，兼职也可以，总之，只要你能得到你需要的，
need but you always get what you need if
但如果你知道自己需要什么，你总能得到你需要的。
talking about boring you borrowed a
说到无聊的事，你从雷那里借了
thousand dollars off Ray yeah Ramon
一千美元，对，拉蒙·
Simone yep Ramon Simone nice name huh
西蒙，没错，拉蒙·西蒙，好名字，对吧？
Ramon Simone wow okay and he was your
拉蒙·西蒙，哇，好吧，他当时是你的
boyfriend at the time he was my
男朋友，他是我
boyfriend I met him at the diner that
男朋友，我在一家餐馆认识他的，那是
was my last Diner job and he offered to
我最后一份餐馆工作，他提出
loan me a thousand dollars to start a
借给我一千美元，让我
business within three months did you ask
三个月内创业。你问
him for the money no he said you've got
他要钱了吗？没有，他说你
a great personality you'd be great in
性格很好，你很适合做
real estate sales why don't you start a
房地产销售，为什么不自己
business and that's how it happened
创业呢？事情就是这样发生的，真的。是的，
really yeah so he had a gift for seeing
他显然很有眼光，能发现
Talent obviously
人才，
you know
你知道的。
and then off you go 24 years old you
然后你就开始了，24岁，你
started you're right 23 but 23. let me
开始了，对，23岁，但是23岁。让我
tell you something thank God at 23 you
告诉你一件事，感谢上帝，23岁的时候你
don't know what to be afraid of
不知道该害怕什么，
you don't know what falling off a
你不知道从
Cliff's about and at 23 and poor
悬崖上掉下去是什么感觉。  23岁，又穷，
you have nothing to lose there was no
你一无所有，也没什么可失去的，没有任何
risk involved I could always get my
风险。我可以随时
Diner job back or any waitress job or a
回去当餐厅服务员，或者任何服务员的工作，或者
pool hander I had millions of jobs I
台球助理，我
could get I wasn't afraid of being
可以找到的工作有无数种。我不怕
unemployed so I figured what the heck
失业，所以我想，管他呢，
I'll try it let's see where it goes
试试看吧，看看结果如何。
however what I didn't know and when the
然而，我当时并不知道，直到我
light went on in my head was I didn't
灵光一闪，我才意识到，我根本不
know how much I would like being a boss
知道自己有多喜欢当老板。
first day I'm like I love this did I
第一天上班，我就感觉自己爱上了这份工作。我喜欢
like real estate I didn't really care
房地产吗？我其实
about real estate did I like the people
对房地产并不感兴趣。我喜欢
I was meeting they're all nice but I had
我遇到的那些人吗？他们都很友善，但我这辈子遇到的都是
been meeting nice people my whole life
友善的人。
but I love the fact that I was in charge
但我喜欢的是掌控一切的感觉。
and so I loved real estate I love the
所以我爱上了房地产，爱上了这些
people I love the paint on the wall I
人，爱上了墙上的油漆，
loved everything because I was a boss I
爱上了一切，因为我是个老板，我
was bent meant for being a boss I felt
天生就是当老板的料。我感到无比
so freed
自由，可以自由地
so free to dream and do whatever I
梦想，自由地做任何我
wanted and nobody could tell me what to
想做的事，没有人可以告诉我该怎么
do it was just it was the greatest gift
做。这简直是最大的礼物——自由！自由！光是
I'm getting juicy just talking about it
说说就让我兴奋不已。
[Laughter]
[笑声]
that real estate company became very big
那家房地产公司发展得非常庞大，
am I right in thinking it became the
我没记错的话，它成了
um residential firm in New York yes
纽约最大的住宅房地产公司。是的，
before I sold it we were number one the
在我卖掉它之前，我们是纽约排名第一的
biggest residential real estate firm in
住宅房地产公司。
why
为什么呢？
because there's so many residential
因为纽约的住宅房地产公司太多了，
real estate people they're everywhere I
房地产从业人员也太多了，他们无处不在。我的
mean every person I meet is in real
意思是，我在纽约遇到的每个人都在做
estate in New York so how do you become
房地产。那么，如何才能成为
the best
最好的呢？说
honestly I think uh there's a lot of
实话，我认为
reasons how you succeed right but I
成功的原因有很多，对吧？但我
think the major cards were
认为最关键的一点是，
I was competing with the old boys
我当时是在和一群老顽固竞争，
network and they were asleep at the
而他们却疏于管理。
it's not that they didn't do good work
并不是说他们工作做得不好，
but you have to realize real estate
但你必须意识到，在
Brokerage in New York when I was started
我刚入行的时候，纽约的房地产经纪行业（
and I guess it's somewhat the same was
我想现在的情况也差不多）是由一些继承了
the business from their father or their
父辈或
grandfather before them so they were
祖辈生意的富人掌控的。他们
very important very self-important very
非常重要，非常自负，受过良好的
well educated very good at what they did
教育，业务能力也很强，
but they did the same old thing they did
但他们仍然沿用老一套的做法，而且他们雇佣的都是和他们一样的
people like themselves they were white
人，他们是白人
privileged and they hired white
特权阶层，他们雇佣白人
privileged women to work for them that
特权阶层的女性为他们工作。总之，
was a whole cast of characters when I
当时的房地产经纪行业可谓是鱼龙混杂。 我
came in I couldn't get those white
刚入行的时候，根本招不到那些
privileged women to work for me because
享有特权的白人女性为我工作，因为
I was a kid I didn't know anything and
我当时还是个毛头小子，什么都不懂，而且这份工作也没有任何地位可言。
with it we were a new kid in town we had
我们刚到镇上，只有
three people who was going to work for
三个人愿意为
me I had a big barn steel to get anybody
我工作。我费了九牛二虎之力才招到人，
to work for me and so they were cocky
所以他们都很自大。
and the minute I smelled that they were
我一察觉到他们的
cocky which happened to me about the
傲慢，就意识到了这一点。大概在我
third year in business when I went to a
创业的第三年，我去参加了
large real estate Board of New York
纽约一个大型房地产协会的活动。
meaning I I was I remember I went home
我记得我回家
and I said I'm going to beat these guys
后就说，我要打败这些人。
and I knew it because they were very
我知道我肯定能做到，因为他们太
cocky that they were in charge and what
自大了，觉得自己掌握着主动权。而这种自大恰恰成了他们
weakness did that create a tremendous
最大的
weakness they're blind it's like
弱点：他们太盲目了。这就像
competing with blind people they were
和盲人竞争一样。他们
also Rich enough not to want to lose
也很有钱，所以不想在
money when the market went South which
市场下跌时赔钱。
happens again and again in real estate
房地产
it's up down Market they would not spend
市场总是起起伏伏，他们不会轻易投资，而是把
money they would hold their money in and
钱囤起来
protect it they would not take a chance
保护好。他们不会冒险，
because of the reputation they would
因为他们要维护自己的声誉。他们会
check check what they were going to do
仔细审查自己的决策，确保不会
against the committee I didn't have
违反委员会的规定。我当时并没有设立
committees they would check what they
委员会，他们会审查…… 他们打算和
were going to do against their attorneys
他们的律师对抗，
they had attorneys they were all stop
他们有律师，但他们都是些只会横亘在路上的
signs I would think of an idea on a
绊脚石。我周二想到一个点子，
Wednesday they would think of an idea on
周三就能把它推向市场。他们周二也想不出点子，
Tuesday if they even thought of it or if
如果他们真的想到了的话，或者如果
they listened to a good employee who had
他们听取了某个好员工的建议（而
a good idea which tended not to do it
好员工往往不会采纳），
was always their ideas but if they list
他们的想法总是被否决的。但如果他们
listen to that employee they'd have to
听取了员工的建议，他们就得
check it with the committee work it up
先跟委员会确认，然后
the line talk to their dad talk to the
逐级上报，跟他们的上司沟通，跟律师沟通。
attorneys I'm like thank God they're in
我心想，谢天谢地，他们陷入了
quicksand so I think a big reason why I
困境。所以我认为我
was able to succeed is because I
能够成功的一个重要原因是，我
competed against the norm of an old boy
挑战了老男孩
network if I had to compete with other
俱乐部式的竞争模式。如果我必须和其他像
people like me wanting to prove
我一样渴望证明自己、拼命想有所作为的人竞争，
I would have had that hunger to compete
我也会充满这种竞争的渴望。
with these guys weren't Hungary they
这些人并不像我一样充满斗志，他们
were well-fed and well vacationed and
吃得饱，度假也过得很好，
they liked it that way
他们就喜欢这样。
one of the things I took from that is um
我从中学到的一点是，
whenever you're competing against like a
当你和一个
big complacent
自满、
slow incumbent being the opposite of the
迟缓的巨头竞争时，与巨头截然相反
incumbent is the winning strategy you
才是制胜之道。你要行动
were quick because you didn't have that
迅速，因为你…… 没有那种
bureaucracy old sign off for lawyers you
官僚主义，律师审批流程繁琐，你
were like high risk you are agile
就像高风险人物，你很灵活，
and you were naive
也很天真。
you know what else I had which isn't to
你知道我还有什么吗？这可不是要
be underestimating I had a wonderful
低估我，我
imagination I would think of the
想象力丰富。我每天都会想出各种
greatest [__] to create publicity
荒唐的点子来制造话题。
every day of the week I just would dream
我会
up some stupid stuff
编造一些愚蠢的东西，然后
and give it to the papers or the or the
交给报纸、电视台或
TV stations I would churn out reports
媒体。我会炮制一些
that I had no business turning out but I
我根本不该写的报道，但我每
could think of an idea a minute and I
分钟都能想到一个点子，然后就
would just throw it out there and see
抛出来，看看会
what happened uh nobody was thinking of
发生什么。呃，当时
new ideas in real estate it was about
房地产行业没人会考虑新点子，大家都在想着如何
controlling the listing market and
控制房源市场，如何
controlling the number of bodies working
控制
for you that was the only game in town
为你工作的人数，这就是唯一的游戏规则。
not how you did it or what differently
没人关心你怎么做，或者
you could do nobody even really was
你能做出什么创新。没人真正
concerned about the customer or the
关心客户或
sellers they just want to know if they
卖家，他们只想知道自己是否认识
had a contact with them because it was a
对方，因为这是个
contact game but I came into a different
关系游戏。但我进入了一个不同的
generation where contacts meant Less in
时代，在纽约，人脉的重要性降低了。
New York as the Waters of New York
随着纽约的
changed and everybody started coming to
变迁，来自
New York at different nationalities and
不同国家、
different colored colors of people
不同肤色的人开始涌入纽约，
everything was changing and these guys
一切都在改变，这些人
really thought it was not changed you
真的开始思考了。 你知道，情况并没有改变，
know so it was such an advantage to have
所以拥有
a lot of ideas and to have to have
很多想法是个巨大的优势，而且你必须招募
tattered soldiers anybody to get your
任何衣衫褴褛的士兵，
hands on and to make them believe they
让他们相信自己和那些
were as good as the fancy people and my
光鲜亮丽的人一样优秀。我的
people believe they were as good and you
员工相信他们一样优秀，你
know what they were as good and they
知道吗？他们确实一样优秀，而且
were better in the end because they all
最终他们更胜一筹，因为他们都
hustled and they all had something to
拼尽全力，都想
prove you know we were all the poor kids
证明自己。你知道，我们都是穷小子，努力
trying to make it make it in New York
在纽约闯出一片天地。
you know so we were all driven you know
所以我们都很有干劲，某种程度上
we're soulmates in a way
我们是灵魂伴侣。
fat company culture and that like
公司文化，还有
philosophy you're citing that as being
你提到的那种理念，是
really pivotal to to why you were
你成功的关键所在。
culture and how do you go about creating
文化是什么意思？你如何创造
that culture yeah the main the main
这种文化？是的，关键在于和
character is having fun with your people
员工一起享受乐趣。
all right I put fun before anything I
我把乐趣放在首位。我的
mean I certainly wanted to drive sales
意思是，我当然想努力提升销售业绩，
hard open new offices hire new people
开设新办公室，招聘新员工，
nurture great management system all the
培养优秀的管理体系——所有
things that go into any business but
任何企业都需要的要素——但更重要的是，
more than that I wanted to make sure
我想确保
everybody loved each other and the way
每个人都彼此喜欢。
you get to break down barriers between
你要打破
people who all compete with each other
彼此竞争的人之间的隔阂，
remember in sales you like who you're
记住，在销售行业，你喜欢谁？ 你和他们一起
working with but you don't really
工作，但你并不
totally like them because they're after
完全喜欢他们，因为他们觊觎
your market so you have friend enemies
你的市场，所以从某种意义上说，你既是朋友又是敌人。
really in a way and so I believe that
我相信，
you uh if you had enough fun with your
如果你和你的团队玩得足够开心，那会是一种
people it was a great equalizer when
很好的平衡器。当
people laugh together they come up with
人们一起欢笑时，他们会迸发出
new ideas when people laugh together
新的想法；当人们一起欢笑时，
they loosen up I used to have people uh
他们会放松下来。我以前会让人们
dressed for my party so they couldn't
打扮成1940年代或1950年代的风格来参加我的派对，这样他们就进不来了。
come in I would have them addressed
我会让他们穿成那样，比如四五十年代的。
1940s 1950s I had them cross-dress oh
我让他们男扮女装，哦，这
what a rebellion at the Kingdom the
在王国里简直是一场叛逆！那些
straight guys I'm not cross-dressing for
直男们当然不会为了
her of course they cross-dressed for me
她而男扮女装，他们当然会为了我而男扮女装。
I had a party where everybody dressed as
我举办过一个派对，每个人都打扮成
a nun I'm not going as enough of course
修女。当然，他们不会为了我而
picnics parties I would take the women
男扮女装，他们当然会来。你知道在华尔道夫酒店的宴会厅里看到一千个修女参加派对是多么令人兴奋吗？那真是太棒了，太有趣了！所以我们会举办野餐派对，我会突然带女人们出去，
spontaneously hey come with me we're
嘿，跟我来，我们
going downstairs to Barney and buying a
下楼去巴尼买件
new underwear why because it's so
新内衣。为什么？ 因为这事儿
bizarre and they all go down and pick
太离奇了，他们都跑去
out the most expensive underwear they
挑最贵的内衣。
could find I mean this bizarre stuff
我的意思是，这些奇奇怪怪的事儿
made them tell everybody who wasn't in
让他们到处跟人说，天哪，
the coming oh God guess what we did it
猜猜我们干了什么？简直是
was an adventure and sooner or later
一场冒险！
what happened after about I guess maybe
大概过了
10 12 years I didn't have to recruit
10到12年，我就不用
anymore our reputation as being the best
再招人了。我们公司作为最佳
place to work started recruiting for us
工作场所的名声开始帮我们招人，
my sales people recruited for us just by
我的销售人员就靠着
repeating stories that happened every
每天讲的故事帮我们招人。
day and so I do believe you create a
所以我相信，
great imaginative culture if you could
如果你能坚持把精力放在策划娱乐活动上，就能​​创造一种充满想象力的企业文化。我说的
Christmas party we drink nothing like
娱乐活动可不是那种无聊的圣诞派对，我们喝酒什么的，而是用
that some bizarre means of having fun
一些奇特的方式来娱乐。
everybody he doesn't have enough fun and
每个人都觉得不够开心，所以
they want to stay with you I had no
他们想留下来。
turnover in my company none in a
我的公司人员流动率很低，在一个人员
business that's loaded with turnover of
流动率很高的行业里，我公司一个
course I fired a third of my staff
员工都没离职。当然，我每年都会解雇三分之一的员工，
every year because they couldn't sell
因为他们卖不出去东西。
but other than the ones I couldn't sell
但除了那些卖不出去的，
no one ever left for another firm they
没有人会跳槽到其他公司。他们
had too much fun at us why would they
在我们公司玩得太开心了，为什么要
leave for the same commission spread I
为了同样的佣金比例离开呢？
don't think so
别这么想。
five years in to that business to that
五年后，
Venture Ramon Simone runs off with your
拉蒙·西蒙和你的
PA yes she's much prettier than I 10
私人助理跑了。是的，她比我漂亮多了，比我
years younger I don't blame him in
年轻十岁。事后想想，我不怪他。
hindsight I don't blame him at the time
当时我不喜欢这样，因为
he was your boyfriend at the time he was
他当时是你的男朋友，也是
my boyfriend at the time he was my 51
我的男朋友。他是我的51号
business partner because he took 51 he
商业伙伴，因为他拿走了51号股份。他
said because he was financing The Firm
说是因为他为公司提供资金，
which was fair I was a managing partner
这很公平。我是管理合伙人，
I like the way that sounded uh yes but
我喜欢这种说法。嗯，是的，但是，
uh he ran off with my business with my
他带着我的
secretary uh the seventh year we were in
秘书跑了，抢走了我的公司。在我们合作的第七年，是的，
that was shocking I didn't expect that
这太令人震惊了，我没想到会这样。
but you know those blows that happened
但你知道，这种打击，尤其是在
to you egos seem the worst at the time
自尊心受损的时候，当时感觉最糟糕，
but it doesn't take you long to realize
但你很快就会明白
what why they happen and why they're the
为什么会发生这些事，以及为什么它们是
best things I mean if he didn't run off
最好的。我的意思是，如果他没有
with her I would have never started the
和她跑了，我就不会创办
Corker group I would still be Corcoran
科克集团，我仍然会是科克伦，和
someone working with him I mean that got
他一起工作。我的意思是，这件事让
me off my butt to start my own company
我立刻行动起来，在
without his help right away because I
没有他帮助的情况下创办了自己的公司，因为我
was a scorned woman and I couldn't stand
当时…… 我是一个被抛弃的女人，我实在受不了
seeing them throw kisses at each other
看到他们
during the work day it drove me crazy
在工作日里卿卿我我，这让我抓狂，
and so I left I just left we cut the
所以我离开了，就这么走了。我们把
company in half at the time we only had
公司裁掉了一半，当时只有
14 people he took seven I took seven and
14个人，他带走了7个，我也带走了7个，然后
off I went thank God that happened
我就走了。谢天谢地，我离开了。
and then he gave me those wonderful
然后，他给了我那句美好的
parting words he'll never succeed
临别赠言：“他永远不会……”
without me thank you Ray
没有我也能成功，谢谢你，雷。
did that drive you those words for I was
那些话是不是你听了之后说的？因为我当时是
the physicist when he said that I was
物理学家，他说那话的时候，我感觉很
like vicious I hated him for it but I
恶毒，我恨他，但我还是
walked out the door hating him for it I
冲出办公室，恨他。
hated him for it the next month the year
接下来的一个月，第二年，我都恨他。然后
after that and then Europe did that and
欧洲也发生了类似的事情，然后我
then I started thinking a word really
开始认真思考。是的，
I realized it was a gift you know insult
我意识到这是一种天赋，你知道，侮辱
uh can really be a wonderful motivator
真的可以成为激励我在《
on Shark Tank I love it when I can find
创智赢家》节目中投资的创业者的绝佳动力。我喜欢那些有着
in an entrepreneur that had a horrible
糟糕父亲、事业遭遇挫折的创业者，
because they're angry they're angry and
因为他们很愤怒，他们很愤怒，
they have more to prove I love an
他们还有更多需要证明的东西。我喜欢
entrepreneur like that I relate to them
这样的创业者，我能理解他们。
that prejudice you you experienced in in
你在
that male dominated industry is it
那个男性主导的行业中经历过的偏见，
easier to manipulate people when they
当人们
have a prejudice against you
对你抱有偏见时，是不是更容易操纵他们？
first of all you have to realize they
首先，你必须意识到他们
didn't see me I was invisible to them
没有看到我，我对他们来说是隐形的，他们没有认真对待我，
they didn't take me seriously why would
他们为什么要认真
they take me seriously even the day I
对待我？即使在我
realized I was invisible I realized I
意识到自己隐形的那一天，我也意识到我
had to Advantage I said nobody's
必须利用优势。我说，没有人
watching me does that make them easy to
关注我，这难道不……
manipulate these men
这些人很容易被操控，嗯，
well I don't know if it meant I
我不知道这算不算我
manipulated them but it was easier to
操控了他们，但
compete with them because the word
跟他们竞争确实更容易，因为“操控”这个词听起来像个
word but at the end of the day if
脏字。但说到底，如果
someone is thinking that you don't
有人觉得你无关紧要，对
you or they are sexist towards you
你不尊重，或者对你性别歧视，他们的
they're underestimation seems like an
低估对你来说似乎就是一个
opportunity it's a great opportunity
机会，一个绝佳的机会。
um you know who was easy to manipulate
你知道谁最容易被操控吗？
though because when the business got
因为当公司
large we were more dependent on huge
规模扩大后，我们更加依赖大型
development sites where they had three
开发项目，那些项目通常有三
four hundred condos for sale we'd have
四百套公寓出售，我们必须
to get control of that building and I
控制那些楼盘。我
was a Salesman who got the control I
是个销售员，负责控制那些楼盘。我
went out after the developers uh the
去找开发商，呃，
as a Woman They had all men working for
作为女人，你很容易操控开发商。他们的员工全是男人，
them it was a man's world real estate uh
房地产是个男人的世界。呃，
the developers uh didn't take me
开发商根本不把我当回事，
seriously at all but I flirted I could
但我会调情，我会出其不意，我会
jolt I wore short skirts I dressed well
穿短裙，我会穿
in tight suits I played my cards I wore
紧身西装，我会耍手段，我会穿高跟鞋，
high heels even though my feet were
即使我的脚疼得要命。是的，
killing me yeah did I manipulate them of
我操控他们了吗？当然，我操控了他们。
course I did did I tell them they looked
告诉他们他们看起来
handsome they were all handsome did I
很帅，他们都很帅。我有没有
tell them they were brilliant you're
告诉他们他们很聪明？你很
brilliant they were all brilliant did I
聪明，他们都很聪明。我有没有
manipulate yes I don't even think I'll
操纵他们？是的，我甚至觉得我
go to heaven I if you want to call it
上不了天堂。如果你非要称之为操纵，那就是
manipulation
操纵
your Workforce if I if I spoke to one of
你的员工。如果我跟
your employees and said
你的一个员工说，我
Barbara like to work with would you
喜欢和芭芭拉一起工作，你
imagine they would say to me I know what
觉得他们会怎么说？我知道
they would say and you won't believe me
他们会怎么说，你肯定不信，
they would say I love Barbara well she
他们会说“我喜欢芭芭拉”。好吧，她
actually spoke to your assistant oh you
其实跟你的助理说了。哦，你做得不错。她肯定会
did well she's gonna lie
撒谎，
Emily yeah she said you were a nightmare
艾米丽。是啊，她说你简直是个噩梦。
and I'm joking you wouldn't say that but
我开玩笑的，你不会这么说的。但
you know you have to ask you have to
你知道，你必须问，你必须
realize who you're asking Emily is an
意识到你在问谁。艾米丽是人间
absolute angel on Earth she has never
天使，她从来没有过不开心的
had a bad day I don't I I wish I was her
日子。我没有，我真希望我是她，
she's incredible so you can't ask her
她太棒了。所以你不能问她，
you have to ask a son of a [__] who
你得去问问我的一个下属。
works for me what would they say they
他们会怎么说？他们会
would say we love Barbara I'm telling
说“我们喜欢芭芭拉，我告诉
you and I deserve it I don't mean to
你，我值得”。我不是想
brag but I am the best boss I've ever
吹牛，但我绝对是我
met by far and I don't think anyone
见过的最好的老板。 说实话，我觉得没人
could be a better boss than me honest to
能比我更适合当老板。
God and I think the root of being a good
我认为，成为好
boss is from the very first day I was in
老板的根本在于，从我创业的第一天起，
business I understood the cardinal rule
我就明白一条基本原则：
which is I work for you you don't work
我为你工作，
for me and that's my attitude my entire
而不是你为我工作。我
life what can I do for you how can I
一生都秉持着这种态度：我能为你做什么？如何
make a job earlier easier what don't you
让你的工作更轻松？你不喜欢做什么？你更愿意做什么？
could I be this for you what what else
我能为你做些什么？
do you do you want I I shower my people
你还想要什么？我会
selflessly and you'd say well that
无私地满足员工的一切需求。你可能会说，这并没有让
doesn't put the boss ahead it does
老板凌驾于他人之上。但事实并非如此，因为
because as they get stronger and go up
随着员工能力的提升和职位的晋升，
the rank they carry me for a free ride
他们会带着我一起顺风顺水。事情就是这样。
along with them that's how it goes no I
不，我
do believe the key to being a big a big
相信，成为一个优秀的
boss a growing boss and a great boss is
老板、一个不断成长的老板、一个伟大的老板的关键在于，
really understand you work for who's
真正理解你是在为那些为
working for you it's as simple as that
你工作的人工作。就这么简单。
you know it's kind of like being a good
你知道，这有点像做一个好
mother in a way you're slave to your
母亲，在某种程度上，你是
kids you just want to please your
孩子的奴隶，你只想取悦你的
children you know I've been thinking
孩子。你知道，我
about something recently about how um
最近一直在思考一些关于
leadership isn't about being and this
领导力的问题。 领导力并非在于一成不变，这话
kind of sounds like it's wrong but let
听起来好像不对，但让
me explain leadership isn't about being
我解释一下。领导力并非在于
consistent with your people some people
对团队成员一视同仁。
in your team will require a certain type
团队中有些人需要某种特定的
of treatment to get the best out of them
对待方式才能发挥他们的最佳潜能，
and then some people in your team will
而有些人则
require probably the opposite treatment
可能需要截然相反的对待方式
to get the best out of them do can you
才能发挥他们的最佳潜能。你
relate to that does that strike so can I
对此有共鸣吗？这话是不是很有道理？所以我想
tell you it's a misnomer that you would
告诉你，认为应该一视同仁地
treat anyone like someone else no I was
对待所有人是错误的。不，我对
biased with every single person who work
每个与我共事的人都有自己的偏好。我
with me I would do different things for
会根据每个人的需求采取不同的做法。
I would just really size them up what's
我会认真评估他们，思考什么能帮助
going to push this kid ahead what's
这个人进步，什么能增强
going to make this person have
这个人的
confidence what could I do to and I had
自信心，我能为他们做些什么。我对
a different formula for everyone no I
每个人都有不同的方法。不，我
think the key was knowing each
认为关键在于了解每个
individual and what floats their boat
人，了解他们的喜好，了解什么
what's important to them what's going to
对他们来说最重要，什么能让
make them better no I was never even
他们变得更好。不，我从来没有公平对待过
handed ever with any of the people I
任何与我
worked with because they were all
共事的人，因为他们都是
individuals and today more than ever
独立的个体。如今，
people really want to be individuals
人们比以往任何时候都更渴望成为独立的个体，
they want to be treated as individuals
他们希望被当作独立的个体来对待，他们
they their interests first you know I I
的利益至上。你知道，我经常
meet a lot of my peers who complain that
遇到我的同行…… 那些抱怨
uh the modern day worker is it wants to
现代员工总是想
be promoted fast wants their interest
快速晋升、希望自己的利益得到
best out of people yeah no that's the
满足的人，我心想，这没问题，我一直都是这么做的。你知道，这才是管理员工的正确方法，才能最大限度地发挥员工的潜力。没错，这才是正确的做法。不管
way to go wherever that philosophy came
这种理念从何而来，
from they haven't created a big team or
他们要么没组建过一个大团队，要么
they know better what characteristic
就更懂行。
would I have to demonstrate working for
我得展现出什么样的特质，才能
you that would make you fire me quickest
让你最快地解雇我？
fire you yeah attitude okay absolutely
解雇你？没错，态度。好吧，绝对的。
uh you know what happens is as careful
你知道，
as I was to hire and I control the
我曾经非常谨慎地招聘，而且在公司成立的头十年里，我一直掌控着
hiring for probably the first 10 years
招聘流程，
of my business until we got to 500
直到员工人数达到500
people and went past that I couldn't do
人。超过这个数字之后，我就做不到了。
it anymore I did some but not a lot
我偶尔会这么做，但不多。
what I would love to do is call someone
我最想做的就是周五把人叫到
to my office on Friday I love firing
办公室来。我喜欢在周五解雇
people on Friday I would stop by
员工。我会在
someone's desk on a Wednesday and say
周三走到某个人的办公桌旁，问他：“
hey would you have any time sometime on
嘿，你
Friday they should have heard about the
周五有空吗？”他们应该已经听说了那些
rumors yes what time is good for you too
传言。“是的，你什么时候方便？”“
see you too I couldn't wait till they
再见。”我迫不及待地想等到他们来上班就解雇
came in to fire them you know why
他们。你知道为什么吗？
because I picked out individuals who
因为我已经挑选好了…… 那些
were negative and my attitude toward the
消极的人，我对他们的态度
negative person was they were ruining my
是，他们毁了我的
good kids because people who are
好孩子，因为
negative have to have somebody else to
消极的人需要别人跟
be negative with them they got to talk
他们一起消极，他们需要
to somebody complain okay I'm not
找人倾诉，需要抱怨。我说的不是
talking about people who tell you what
那些告诉你哪里
you're doing wrong they're invaluable so
做得不对的人，他们非常宝贵，能让
that you can get better I'm telling my
你进步。我说的是那些
chronic complainers and negative people
总是抱怨、消极的人，
you gotta get rid of them so I learned
你必须把他们赶走。所以，在
after firing one negative person never
解雇一个消极的人之后，我很快就明白了，永远不要
tell them why you're firing them
告诉他们你为什么要解雇他们，
okay or you're getting a Rat's Nest why
否则你会遇到一堆麻烦事。“为什么
am I negative why aren't I so no you
我这么消极？为什么我不消极？”不，你
just don't fit the company but why I
只是不适合这家公司。至于为什么，我
don't know you just don't fit the
不知道，你就是不适合这家
company maybe that's a little mean but I
公司。也许这有点刻薄，但我从来
never carried a negative person for more
不会让一个消极的人待
than a couple of months sometimes
超过几个月。有时候
they're undercover at first but
他们一开始会隐藏起来，但
eventually they come out like hey do you
最终他们会露出真面目，比如“嘿，你
have any time on Friday
周五有空吗？”
[Music]
[音乐]“
if you ever ask me for a meeting on
如果你周五约我开会，
I'll take the Friday off
我就周五请假。”天哪，
blimey why why are you so irked by
为什么你这么讨厌
complainers and is there is it something
抱怨的人？是不是跟那些
about the thieves
小偷有关？
they're thieves they take your money
他们是窃贼，他们偷走你的钱
away and they take your energy and the
，偷走你的精力。精力
most valuable asset you have is your
是你最宝贵的资产，
and if they take your energy away you're
如果他们偷走了你的精力，你就
not going to deliver enough to everybody
无法为其他人提供足够的服务，也无法满足所有人的需求。
else is not enough to go around no
不，
they're thieves in the night they come
他们是夜里的窃贼，
in they got their hands in your pockets
他们潜入你的口袋，
and they're taking your goods that's how
偷走你的财物。这就是
I see negative people when you have a
我看待消极的人的方式。当你的
team filled with very positive people
团队里都是积极向上的人时，
it's like they're stuffing your pockets
就像他们一直在往你的口袋里塞满
with money and jewels all the time it's
金钱和珠宝。这就是
the way you want to be it's those people
你想要成为的样子，这就是你
you want to be around have you noticed
想要与之相处的人。你注意到了吗？
because I think I've noticed this that
因为我觉得我注意到了这一点。
you know my my first business where we
你知道，在我第一家公司，我们
had about somewhere around 500 people
大约有500名员工，
95 of my people problems were created by
95%的人事问题都是由
like one person of course the complainer
一个人造成的，当然，就是那个爱抱怨的人，那个
yeah the negative person you didn't ever
消极的人。你从来不在
work on Friday
周五上班。
no do you know what I didn't realize I
你知道吗？我当时没有意识到，我
should have just made the decision
应该迅速做出决定，把他/她
quickly to get rid of them but then I I
开除。但我当时有
had that complex which bosses sometimes
那种老板有时会有的心理障碍，
have where I go well if I get rid of
我会想，如果我把他/她开除……
them then it's going to impact the
这会影响公司
culture and then they're going to do
文化，然后他们就会
this and sometimes there's so much of a
这么做。有时候，
complainer and so negative they've
抱怨的人太多，太消极了，以至于他们身边的人都开始抱怨了。我当时
there was this fear that if I if I fire
担心，如果我解雇
them then there's going to be even more
他们，消极情绪会更加严重，就像
negativity like like a volcano of
火山爆发一样。
yeah sure you found very differently
你当时太天真了。是啊，你解雇他们之后发现情况完全不同了。阿门。是啊，阿门。
once you fired amen yeah amen I learned
我吸取了教训。我现在奉行的原则之一就是，一旦你知道了什么，就尽快知道。你说的“不要说是因为
um don't say it's because they are you
他们就是这样”，你不能这么
can't say because you can't win at that
说，因为你赢不了这种争论。是
game yeah you know it took me probably
啊，你知道，我大概花了
three years I I hired a great salesman
三年时间，才从另一家公司挖来了一位优秀的销售员。那家公司一直想
from another firm which was reaching for
来找
me because I groomed all my own no one
我，因为我自己培养的人才都不够，没人
wanted to come and someone actually
愿意来。结果竟然有人
wanted to come and work for me from a
愿意从一家更大的公司来为我工作，
bigger firm I couldn't believe it I
我简直不敢相信。我
hired this lady she was so negative
雇了这位女士，她一
right away so negative she had two
开始就非常消极，非常消极。面试的时候，她只有2
percents outward when you're
%的外向
interviewing and inward when they're
和2%的内向。 当她们
working for you and she was so so
为你工作，而她却如此
negative and I really thought I could
消极的时候，我真的以为我
change her around I'm such a positive
能改变她。我是一个如此积极乐观的
human being everybody who's positive I'm
人，我相信每个人都是积极向上的，我一定
gonna change her around and then I
能改变她。后来我
learned the important lesson if her
明白了一个重要的道理：如果她的
parents could make her smile I wasn't
父母能让她开心，我永远不会
going to forget it they had this lady
忘记。他们一辈子都和她在一起，而
for their whole life and she's miserable
她却如此痛苦，
I'm not gonna make her happy and so part
我不可能让她快乐。所以，一部分原因
of it is admitting defeat that you're
在于承认失败，承认你
not all that powerful where you're going
没有那么强大的力量去
to turn somebody around no negative you
改变一个人。对于消极的人，你
just get rid of them terrible
只能摆脱他们，这太糟糕了。
let's talk about something positive what
我们来谈谈积极的事情吧，
about compliments
比如赞美。
compliments when they're genuine not
真诚的赞美，而不是
compliments that are empty and not
空洞的赞美，也不是为了
sake of grandstanding I just don't
哗众取宠而在众人面前的赞美。我不
believe in it people see right through
相信这些，人们一眼就能看穿
the [__] you know everybody you
谎言。你知道，就算你
could get somebody with the lowest IQ in
找一个智商最低的人，
the world you [__] them they know it
你胡说八道，他们也知道，他们就是知道。
they just know it you just assume people
你只是假设人们
are smarter than they look okay and so I
比看起来更聪明而已。所以，我
think a genuine compliment with
认为真诚的赞美，并辅以
specifics to back it up is the greatest
具体事例，是
thing in the world and you'll make
世界上最美好的事情。 让
someone fly and become even stronger the
某人飞起来，第二天变得更强大，
next day but if it's not specific and
但如果没有具体说明
why that was so smart that you did and
你这样做有多聪明，以及
what it did for us that's a compliment
它对我们有什么作用，那只是一句空洞的赞美，
let's give her a round of applause okay
让我们为她鼓掌吧。
that's the right kind of comment but you
这才是正确的评论方式。但你
know to find those compliments it is
知道，要找到这些赞美，
creating a habit as a manager or a
作为管理者或
business owner of looking for I would
企业主，你需要养成寻找的习惯。我会
walk through and try to find anything
巡视团队，努力寻找任何
good I could talk about anything anybody
值得称赞的地方，任何值得称赞的事情，任何
did good that somebody would stitch on
值得称赞的事情，
and then I get the details down and then
然后我会记下细节，
give them a compliment individually if I
如果我
thought they're a private person but if
认为他们比较低调，我会单独给予赞美；但如果
I thought they're a competitive person I
我认为他们好胜心强，我
always sit in front of the group because
总是会坐在团队前面，因为
they're competitive and they want
他们好胜心强，希望
everybody to see they're better you know
每个人都看到他们更优秀。
so yeah yes the compliments are so
所以，赞美的力量确实很
powerful but you know they pass I think
强大，但你知道，它们会随着时间流逝。我认为
the greatest compliment you could give
你能给予
an individual is trust that they are
一个人的最好赞美就是相信他们比自己
better than they think they are
想象的更优秀。
and I honestly think that people write
我真心认为，人们常常
themselves off for so much less than
低估自己的
they're capable of
能力。比如，
um when you say to someone I noticed you
当你对某人说“我注意到你的
dress I'll give you an example because
穿着”时，我举个例子，因为
this is a silly example but I got my
这…… 举个有点傻的例子，我的
advertising manager she was a Salesman
广告经理以前是个销售员，业绩平平，勉强能
turning a little profit but not great
达到收支平衡，也略有盈利，但并不出色。
and I looked at her every day and
我每天都看着她，
thought she is such a beautiful dresser
觉得她穿衣打扮真漂亮，
which she can do with her hair with a
她的头发和
clothing is incredible and I went out of
衣服搭配起来简直完美。我
my way to walk over to her desk she had
特意走到她的办公桌前，发现她总能找到最
the perfect match she had the perfect
合适的搭配，
thing her desk looked like I wanted to
她的办公桌布置得美轮美奂，让我恨不得立刻去
vacation there it was so gorgeous so I
那里度假。于是我
said to her Anita how would you like to
对她说：“安妮塔，你愿意
be my advertising manager she said I
做我的广告经理吗？” 她说：“我
didn't know you had an advertising
不知道你们公司有广告
manager I said I don't but how about you
经理。” 我说：“我没有，但你
take it now how did I know she would be
现在就来吧。” 我怎么知道她会
exceptional in advertising because
在广告方面出类拔萃呢？因为
everything about her was put together I
她浑身上下都散发着一种独特的气质。我
figured that how to transfer to great
意识到，她能把这种气质运用到优秀的
graphics beautiful design the land out
平面设计和精美的画面中，让整个公司都为之惊艳。
of the page because she was that was
因为她就像
kind of like a page I saw on her desk
一张精美的画作，而我在她的办公桌上看到的，简直就是一张完美的画作。
she was incredible I I I think you just
她太棒了！我觉得你只
have to find the gift in people and
需要发现别人身上的天赋，
point it out and think how can I take
指出来，然后思考如何利用它。
advantage and Anita became probably the
安妮塔后来成了
in the city because of our great
城里所有公司都羡慕的对象，因为我们出色的
advertising that wasn't me I got the
广告工作。当然，这并不是我一个人的功劳。
credit was her but I blossomed her her
功劳归她，但我让她绽放
up because I saw that gift in her you
光芒，因为我看到了她身上的天赋。你
know sounds like a stretch but it's
知道，这听起来有点牵强，但
really not you know it's not a stretch
其实不然。
if you keep your eyes open and see what
如果你睁大眼睛，看看
people are good at
别人擅长什么，那就不是牵强附会了。
we talked about the mouth there with the
我们之前讨论过嘴部和
smile but what about the eyes
笑容，但眼神呢？
you mean looking at someone in the eyes
你是说看着别人的眼睛？是的，
yeah oh you have to I mean do you trust
你必须这样做。我的意思是，你会信任
anyone who doesn't make eye contact
一个从不和你进行眼神交流的人吗？
ever really there you figure they're
你会觉得他们
either insecure they shift insecure
要么缺乏安全感，要么
dishonest or
不诚实，或者
probably those two that's what I would
可能两者兼有。我会
say dishonest or insecure either way you
说，要么不诚实，要么缺乏安全感，总之，你
don't want to hang out with them no the
不想和他们待在一起。
eyes are key all right because I read
眼神至关重要。因为我读到过，
that in the pandemic when you were
在疫情期间，你
hiring for one of your roles you
招聘某个职位时，
basically there was 500 people and you
基本上有500人，你
basically excluded everybody that didn't
基本上排除了所有不和
make eye contact with the camera you've
镜头进行眼神交流的人。你
read that about me yeah I think it was
读到过关于我的报道吗？是的，我认为
probably exaggerated I don't think it
可能有些夸张，我不认为
was 500 people but just uh you know a
有500人，但确实
lot of people yeah but a lot of people
很多人。是的，确实很多人。好吧，
definitely okay you don't make it
你绝对不会这么做，
absolutely and you excluded everyone who
你排除了所有人。
had bad lighting I did yeah why
灯光不好，确实如此。为什么？
because it showed a lack of
因为这显得缺乏
aggressiveness and caring for themselves
进取心和自我形象。
I felt I mean if I was interviewing for
我觉得，如果我去面试
a job and I knew it was competitive most
一份工作，而且我知道竞争很激烈（大多数
jobs are I would want to show my best
工作都是如此），我会想展现自己最好的一面。我会仔细考虑
self I think through everything I mean
所有事情。
maybe me more than most people would do
也许我比大多数人更注重这一点，
it but I think if you show up with bad
但我觉得如果你在灯光不好的情况下出现，
lighting and then on top of that you
而且还
don't make good eye contact next please
不能进行良好的眼神交流，那就别来了，真的太
no it's just terrible no it's very hard
糟糕了。
to hire people through covet online but
通过Covet在线招聘很难，但
I never did in the end whoever I hired I
我最终从未这样做过。无论我最终雇佣了谁，我都会
insist I meet them in person you can't
坚持与他们见面。
to his thorough job unless you're in
除非面对面，否则你无法真正做好这项工作，
person I believe or I've never been able
我相信，或者说，我一直没能
to learn how to do that I had a few
学会如何做到这一点。
words to say about one of my sponsors on
在这个播客里，我想谈谈我的一个赞助商。
yesterday when I was having a shower and
昨天我洗澡的时候，我女朋友上楼来，
she said to me that she tried the heel
她说她试了放在
protein shake which lives on my fridge
我冰箱里的Heel蛋白奶昔，
over there and she said it's amazing low
她说这奶昔很棒，低
calories you get your 20 odd grams of
卡路里，含有20多克
protein you get your 26 vitamins and
蛋白质、26种维生素和
minerals and it's nutritionally complete
矿物质，营养全面。
in the protein space there's lots of
蛋白质产品琳琅满目，
things but it's hard to find something
但很难找到一款真正
that is nice especially when consumed
好喝的，尤其是
just with water if you haven't tried the
只用水冲泡的。如果你还没试过
heel protein product do give it a try
Heel的蛋白粉，一定要试试
The Salted Caramel one if you put some
咸焦糖口味的。加点冰块，用
blender and you try it is as good as
搅拌机打碎，你会发现它和
pretty much any milkshake on the market
市面上几乎所有奶昔一样好喝，即使只
just mixed with water it's been a game
用水冲泡也一样。它彻底
changer for me because I'm trying to
改变了我的饮食习惯，因为我正在努力
drop my calorie intake and I'm trying to
减少卡路里摄入，也想让饮食更
be a little bit more healthy with my
健康一些。Heel的蛋白粉完美契合了我的
diet so this is where heel fits in my
需求。
life thank you heal for making a product
感谢Heel生产出
that I actually like Intel now one of
我真正喜欢的产品。英特尔是
our sponsors on this podcast and I'm
本期播客的赞助商之一，今天我要
here to tell you about their vpro
介绍的是他们的V-Pro
platform security and data protection
平台。对于我公司使用的技术来说，安全性和数据保护
are totally non-negotiable when it comes
是绝对不容妥协的。
businesses I'm constantly thinking about
我一直在思考如何
where we can upgrade our systems to
升级系统以
protect against potential threats so
抵御潜在威胁，而
this is where Intel V pro has become our
英特尔V-Pro正是我们
go-to Intel V Pro is built for
首选的解决方案。英特尔V-Pro专为
businesses it has a hardware-based
企业打造，拥有基于硬件的
multi-layer platform security features
多层平台安全功能，能够有效
protecting from cyber attacks threat
抵御网络攻击。 在日益严峻的网络环境中，攻击威胁
detection and also recovery systems all
检测和恢复系统都集成
in one platform in an Ever challenging
在一个平台上。
cyber landscape if I can put measures in
如果我能采取一些
place that I believe will save me time
我认为可以节省时间
and money then I absolutely will so head
和金钱的措施，我肯定会这么做。所以，请
over to
访问
intel.co.ukvpro to find out how it could
intel.co.ukvpro，了解它如何
work for your business
为您的企业带来效益。就像《创智赢家》（Shark Tank）一样，我在《龙穴》（Dragon
Dragon's Den you're a shark on Shark
's Den）里是“龙”，你在《创智赢家》里是“鲨鱼”，
Tank all the same yeah means you're a
没错，这意味着你是个
sucker does it to be fair I mean I think
傻瓜，对吧？公平地说，我认为
dragons are slightly more impressive
龙
than sharks I'm gonna be honest you
比鲨鱼更令人印象深刻。说实话，你觉得呢？
think Shy I think sharks are more
我觉得鲨鱼更令人
impressive sharks are real dragons don't
印象深刻。鲨鱼是真实存在的，龙并不
exist we're kind of dragons are silly
存在。我们有点傻，龙就像是老古董，只有
it's an old-fashioned where it's sharks
鲨鱼，
and sharks well sharks well I mean other
只有鲨鱼。我的意思是，除了《
than Jaws what if sharks really done for
大白鲨》之外，如果鲨鱼真的对
society whereas a dragon is you you're
社会有益呢？而龙是你，你是一个拥有
someone of great imagination to to be a
丰富想象力的人。要成为
dragon you have to have great
一条龙，你必须拥有丰富的
imagination because they don't exist
想象力，因为它们并不存在，就像
it's like being a unicorn so can we
独角兽一样。所以我们能
agree that dragons are better I know I'm
同意龙更好吗？我知道，恐怕不行。好吧，
okay well you're on Shark Tank and link
你上车了。 说到《创智赢家》（Shark Tank），以及
to what we just said about quickly
我们刚才讨论的如何快速
assessing if a person is is legit and
评估一个人是否靠谱、是否
worth investing in
值得投资，你有什么心得体会？
what have you learned you've been on the
你参加这个
show longer than I've been on the UK
节目的时间比我在英国
version of the show
版节目里待的时间还长，
as a new Dragon to be successful from
作为一名新晋“龙”，你有什么建议能让我成功？以
your experience I would say keep your
你的经验来说，我会建议你
money in your pocket for a little bit
先把钱留在口袋里一段时间。是
yeah and my first few seasons of Shark
啊，我参加《创智赢家》的前几季，花了
Tank I spent so much money threw money
很多钱，只要有东西在，我就往墙上扔钱。
so I hope you haven't made that mistake
所以我希望你没有犯过同样的错误。我
I needed like 11 investments in my first
第一季就投资了11个项目。
season so but uh for me I what I have
对我来说，我
learned in 14 years and I've learned it
在14年里学到的，其实早在
a good 10 years ago I'd say
10年前就学到了，那就是
is I never choose a business I always
我从不选择投资某个企业，而是
choose the entrepreneur
选择投资人。
I have sat there and listened to
我曾经坐在那里听过一些
business plans that I don't even know
商业计划书，但我根本不知道
what they're talking about I it makes no
他们在说什么，
sense to me what they're talking about
他们说的那些东西对我来说毫无意义，
uh because it's not a business I know or
因为那不是我了解的行业，或者
I don't understand the terminology
我不理解那些术语。
and in the old days I would have thought
以前我会觉得
I was too stupid but now I know I'm
自己太笨了，但现在我知道了。 我
smart enough that if I'm not
足够聪明，即使不
understanding it's okay I'm probably
理解也没关系，我可能
still smart
仍然很聪明。
but I have to be really smart in making
但我必须非常谨慎地选择
the choice of the individual do I trust
对象：我是否信任
this person
这个人？
can I visualize them going through a
我能想象他们能做到力挽狂澜吗？
what's their background are they good at
他们的背景是什么？他们善于
getting back up do they have ambition
东山再起吗？他们有抱负吗？（
not passion passion's so overrated I
激情被高估了。）我对这件事
feel passionate this we really want to
充满热情，我们真的很想
do this like saying you're excited about
做这件事，就像你对
your first date who cares you know where
第一次约会感到兴奋一样。谁在乎呢？你知道，
do you marry the lady and see how you
你最终会娶她，然后看看
feel but I think the commitment and the
感觉如何。但我认为，
drive and the ambition is what I'm
我一直在寻找的是承诺、动力和抱负。
always looking for I'm looking just just
我只是在观察，
trying to smell it out if someone says
试图嗅出其中的端倪。如果有人说
they were poor and they didn't have a
他们很穷，没有
father let's say I'm biased right away I
父亲，假设我一开始就带有偏见，我
want to buy the business
想立刻收购他们的公司，投资他们的公司。但这
doesn't mean I will because I have to
并不意味着我一定会投资，因为我需要
hear more about how they handle things
更多地了解他们如何处理事情，
what kind of an individual they are but
他们是怎样的人。
no I'm very biased or I should really
不，我确实很偏袒富二代，或者更确切地说，
say I'm I'm not very nice or fair-minded
我对富二代不太友好或公正。
the problem with investing in a business
投资
owned by a rich kid is usually raise
富二代的公司通常存在一个问题。
money already rather easily it's not
钱来得很容易，不用靠
Sweat Equity so you got a chunk of
汗水换来，所以你有一大笔钱可以
change to get started okay that's nice
启动，这很好。
now you would think that would make
你可能会觉得这会让
things easier I think it makes things
事情变得更容易，但我认为反而会
difficult you don't spend your money
更难。你没有
wisely it's Papa's money or if or your
明智地花钱，这些钱要么是爸爸的，要么是你
parents friends money or wherever you
父母朋友的，要么是你从哪里弄来的，
got it from so it's not valuable money
所以这些钱并不值钱。
and I've seen more people stand and say
我见过太多人站出来说，
well we pivoted we lost that we pivoted
我们转型了，我们失败了，我们转型了，那些
what happened to the guys that gave me
给我
the cash what happened to them no regard
钱的人呢？他们怎么样了？完全不关心他们。
at all okay when you get a poor kid they
好吧，当你遇到一个穷孩子时，他们
typically have something to prove they
通常都想证明自己，他们
really have to stretch every penny it's
必须精打细算，每一分钱都是他们
their own money they die and just get a
自己的钱，他们死后也只能得到一点点，他们的
greater need and it's also a desire
需求更大，也渴望
to do well in living in their life they
过上好日子，他们
want to go on vacations they too want to
想去度假，他们也想买
get a sports car they want to get a nice
跑车，他们也想买一套好
apartment these rich kids have had it
公寓。这些富家子弟
all before they've been on vacation
以前什么都有，他们去过很多地方度假，他们
everywhere they've always had rich cars
一直开着豪车，
Rich parents so I think it's so much
父母也很富有。所以我认为
harder for rich kid to succeed as an
富家子弟创业要难得多。
entrepreneur I just love poor kids and I
我喜欢穷孩子，我
have to tell you out of my whole
必须告诉你，在我所有的投资
portfolio I don't have a single rich kid
组合中，没有一个富家子弟
who succeeded
成功。
well most of it is because I don't
大部分原因是我
invest in them in the last five years
过去五年没有投资他们，
but even when I did years ago none of
但即使几年前我投资过他们，他们也没有
them succeeded no they went on to do
成功，他们都去做了
something else my poor people those are
其他的事情。我的穷人，他们才是
my winners yeah they're desperate to
我的赢家，是的，他们渴望
succeed
成功，没有什么比
the only thing that beats growing up
成长更重要的了。
poor in cochrane's opinion is growing up
在科克伦看来，贫穷的成长环境会让人受到
damaged oh
伤害。哦，是啊，
well aren't we all damaged in one way or
我们每个人或多或少都会受到伤害，对吧？
but you could get damaged by money and
但金钱和富裕也很容易让人受到伤害。
affluence so easily I think it's easier
我觉得
to raise a poor kid than it is a rich
养育一个贫穷的孩子比养育一个富裕的
kid
孩子更容易，
because of the circles they fly in their
因为他们的
value systems who they measure
价值观体系比较封闭，他们衡量
themselves against what they measure
自己的标准也不同。
I think it's more difficult to be an
我觉得对于
affluent kid or affluent Rich parent and
富裕的孩子或者富裕的父母来说，要
raise a good kid a good kid with values
养育一个有价值观的好孩子更难。
I really think it's harder you know when
我真的觉得这更难。你知道，
I said I spoke to your assistant I did
我说过我和你的助理谈过了，是的，我们谈的是
but we did Emily right yeah okay Emily
艾米丽，对吧？好的，艾米丽，
good thing you talk to the good one oh
幸好你和好人谈了。哦，还有
there's another one there's three and
另一个，有三个，
they don't like me no more okay
他们现在不喜欢我了。好吧，嗯，
um and she told me about some pictures
她跟我说了
in your office that are hanging on the
你办公室墙上挂着的一些照片。
wall oh those
哦，那些是“
what is the whole way of Doom
末日之路”的。什么是“末日之路”？
well you see
你看，
anyone who's on Shark Tank as you
任何上过《创智赢家》（Shark Tank）的人，就像你
well-known Dragon stem has in night in
认识的“龙之源”（Dragon Steam）一样，都会在《太阳报》（Night in the
the Sun
Sun）上亮相，
where they're on the show and everybody
他们在节目里，每个人都
orders from them and they become almost
向他们订购东西，他们几乎
Rich overnight or at least they think
一夜暴富。 至少他们觉得
they're going to be rich and they're all
自己要发财了，大家都在
celebrating excited all right and then
兴奋地庆祝，好吧，然后
something goes wrong with the business
生意就出问题了，
maybe three to four months out that's my
大概三四个月后——这是我的
timetable I'm waiting for that day
时间表——我一直在等那一天。肯定
Something's Gonna go wrong it's not just
出问题了，不只是
the patent didn't come through that's
专利没通过，还有
minor stuff like the mold was wrong
模具出错之类的小事，
where they delivered 10 000 pieces
他们交付的一万件产品都是错的，
they're made wrong and he had the patent
而且他还有专利，
I didn't know he was going to give it to
我不知道他本来打算给
me but he ran off with it
我，结果他拿着专利跑了。肯定出问题了，我就在
something goes wrong I just wait around
旁边等着，
and I watch and I say how's it going
观察着，问问情况怎么样，得到的
and there's only two different responses
回答只有两种：
to that which is he promised me you know
一是他答应过我，你知道，
he promised me I mean the guy said he
他答应过我，我的意思是，那家伙说他很
was good
厉害。二是走到
I go over to my wall and I turn the
墙边，把那位
entrepreneur's picture upside down to
创业者的照片倒过来，
remind myself never to talk to them
提醒自己永远不要再跟他们说话，不要
again or spend time no I'll talk to them
浪费时间。不，我会跟他们说话，
but I'm not going to spend my time
但我不会浪费时间，
because they're victims and then you
因为他们是受害者。然后，还有
have the one in four people who handle
四分之一的人会
it this way ah crap I can't believe I
这样处理：啊，糟糕，我真不敢相信我
made that mistake okay let's let's see
犯了这样的错误。好吧，就这样吧。 让我们看看
what we should do
我们应该怎么做。
that's an entrepreneur
这才是企业家该做的：
moving on moving out and going forward
勇往直前，积极进取，
and taking the blame even if they
即使错不在自己头上，也要承担责任。
weren't to blame every one of my really
我所有真正
successful businesses I've done so well
成功的企业都经历过最
have had the worst setbacks but they've
严重的挫折，但他们
always taken responsibility and those
总是勇于承担责任，而且他们总是能把责任推卸给别人。
pictures are always right side up they
他们会主动
call me on myself hello how can I help
问我：“你好，我能帮
you because they're phenomenal
您什么吗？”因为他们都是非常优秀的
entrepreneurs I believe that the
企业家。我相信，
difference between the really good ones
真正优秀的企业家和失败者之间的区别在于，失败者
ones that don't make it know how to be a
不会自怨自艾，他们只会自怜自艾，把责任推给
they blame the next guy and they don't
别人，而不会
take the responsibility as their own and
承担自己的责任。而
that's what an entrepreneur does you're
企业家应该这样做：你是
the boss it's your problem period it's
老板，这是你的问题，就这么简单，这是
your your problem rest with you now what
你的问题，你自己看着办吧。现在，
are you going to do about it and these
你打算怎么做？这些
kids that are are really equipped to to
年轻人真的有能力
not hesitate at all but just get on the
毫不犹豫地行动，骑上
horse and go Galloping go and go and go
战马，一路狂奔，
and go go going again they're terrific I
他们太棒了！我
invest in uh Four Women cousins who have
投资了四个
a very clever wow I don't know how
非常聪明的表姐妹，哇，我不知道她们有多
clever the business was but I'm their
聪明。 生意确实不好，但他们很
clever over and they lost eight hundred
聪明，每个月损失了80
thousand dollars a month three stolen
万美元，
from their accounts couldn't pay the
账户里被盗了300万美元，付不起
suppliers all of their sales were gone I
供应商的货款，所有销售额都消失了。我
couldn't wait to talk to them I was not
迫不及待地想和他们谈谈，我不想
going to say too bad it happened I said
说“太可惜了”，我说“
hey hi I heard
嘿，你好，我听说了，
what are you gonna do
你们打算怎么办？”。“嗯，我们
well we're thinking already back on the
已经在思考如何重新振作起来了。”
horse they recovered the end of the year
他们在年底恢复了业绩，
dollars in sales how did they do it they
销售额达到了700万美元左右。他们是怎么做到的？他们
are just not victims they go forward
不是受害者，他们不断前进，不断前进，不断
forward forward forward those are the
前进。这些
people I love I love them
人我爱，我爱他们。我
this allergic reaction to complainers
对抱怨者
and pessimists and get back to that
和悲观主义者有种过敏反应，再说回这个话题。
again no but does it come from I was
不，但这是否源于……我
just reflecting on how much your mother
刚才在想你母亲的……
you said you never even saw her sleep no
你说你甚至都没见过她睡觉。不，
she was just or she didn't complain she
她只是……或者说她从不抱怨，她只是默默地做着。
just got on with it is it influenced by
这是否受到了影响？
um I'll tell you what my mother did
嗯，我告诉你我母亲的做法，这确实
which did influence all of us uh if we
影响了我们所有人。如果我们
went to my mother uh with something my
去找我母亲……我
brother John did to me well my sister
哥哥约翰对我做了什么，或者我姐姐
Ellen did to me something unfair we'd go
艾伦对我做了什么不公平的事，我们会去找
to her she took this from me she wasn't
她。她拿走了我的东西，她不
supposed to my mother would punish us
应该拿走的，我母亲会…… 她惩罚我们
both
俩，
she didn't hear the complaints she said
她根本没听进去我们的抱怨，她说：“
you're both punished sit down
你们俩都受罚了，坐下，
you have an hour
一个小时，就这么定了。”
complaining about anything so we never
抱怨什么都没用，所以我们从不
complained we learn in short order as
抱怨。我们从小就明白，你
little kids you don't complain you just
不能抱怨，你只能
shut up otherwise you both get punished
闭嘴，否则你们俩都会受到惩罚。
and you know in business it's really
你知道，在商场上也是
that way if you think about it uh yeah
如此，如果你仔细想想……嗯，
if you're going to complain
如果你要抱怨，
you know I even had an incident I
你知道吗？我甚至经历过一件
learned very early on that just popped
很早就让我明白的事，它突然出现
in my head that reminded me so much of
在我的脑海里，让我想起了
my mother I had two department heads who
我的母亲。我有两个部门主管
hated each other and I wasn't aware of
互相憎恨，但我之前并不知道。后来
it someone brought my attention to it
有人提醒了我。
anyway one came in and told me what why
总之，其中一个来告诉我，为什么
this other department was getting in the
另一个部门总是碍事，
way and the other one in one of them
另一个也在场。
around I said wow this must be terrible
我说：“哇，这对
for you I was empathetic empathetic
你来说一定很糟糕。”我很同情她们，认真
listen to both complaints and then I
听了她们俩的抱怨，然后我
said we here with the second one I went
说：“我们来处理第二个抱怨的人。”我
and got the first complainer and I said
去找了第一个抱怨的人，我说：“
okay girls uh you obviously have a
好了，姑娘们，你们显然在
problem with the way you're working
合作方式上存在问题，自己想办法解决，
together figure it out you're both fired
你们俩都被解雇了。” 我
I was mimicking my mother figure it out
模仿我妈的语气说：“自己想办法解决，
or you're both fine I left the room they
不然你们俩就都完了。”我离开了房间，
you know what all my friends call Bill
他们自己想明白了，之后再也没来找我抱怨过。你知道吗？这招对谁都管用，你知道吗？这招对谁都管用，公司文化方方面面都是这样。比尔，比尔，哦，该死的比尔，你知道我所有的朋友都怎么称呼比尔吗？
poor Bill this is not a shame I'm the
可怜的比尔。这没什么丢人的，我才是
nice person bill is a difficult man and
好人。比尔是个难搞的人，
yet everybody who knows us both calls
可是所有认识我们的人都叫
him poor Bill like he married the wrong
他可怜的比尔，好像他娶错
person
人了似的。那
that is your husband yes 37 years he
是你丈夫，没错，37年了。他
said he's the nice one and you're the
说他是好人，你是
difficult one who said that you spoke to
难搞的人。谁说你跟
Bill you spoke to Bill yeah don't
比尔谈过了？你跟比尔谈过了？是啊，别
believe it
信。
I can't believe he even answered the
我都不敢相信他居然接了
phone he's always watching TV I didn't
电话，他总是看电视。我没
speak to him oh gosh
跟他说话。哦，天哪，
you know ironically if you did speak
你知道吗，讽刺的是，如果你真的
with Bill Bill adores the ground I walk
跟比尔谈过了，比尔会把我捧上天，从来
on can never say anything negative and
不会说我的坏话。而
all I do is complain about Bill
我却只会抱怨比尔，只会
and all I do is say negative things
说他的坏话。
I really mean it I'm a terrible wife
我是认真的，我是个糟糕的妻子，我
I really am not just saying that but you
真的不是随便说说。你
should talk to Bill he'll confirm this I
应该跟比尔谈谈，他会证实这一点的。我谈过了。
did and he'd confirmed it I did your
他证实了，我做了你那
terrible um the thing I was really
糟糕的……嗯，真正让我印象
compelled by is I was reading how at
深刻的是，我读到
some point you started out earning Bill
你一开始的收入超过了比尔，
yes and that in a relationship can have
是的，这在一段关系中会产生
an interesting Dynamic on the like
一种有趣的动态，比如对这段
on the relationship yeah because of the
关系的影响，是的，因为这些
stuff definitely and that's what I was
事情，绝对是这样。这就是我
reading about your story about it being
读到你的故事时所感受到的，你们的关系一度很
a struggle at some point you first lied
艰难。你第一次撒谎说你的
out earned him for the first time you
收入超过了他，你把这归咎于
put it down to an accounting error and
会计错误，而且
you seem to kind of not want to
你似乎不太想承认。
it was tough at first you know when I
你知道，一开始很艰难。当我
met Bill he owned a brokerage firm in
遇到比尔时，他在新泽西州拥有一家经纪公司，
New Jersey and I earned I had one in New
而我在纽约也有一家，
York I had 19 20 people here 19 20
我们有19到20名员工，
people we were even right and then
我们势均力敌。然后在
within the next four years I had 500
接下来的四年里，我的员工人数达到了500
people and he had 22.
人，而他只有22人。
not a good scene all right we're both
情况不太妙。好吧，我们俩的
earning about just able to pay our rent
收入都差不多只能勉强支付房租。
kind of when we got married
结婚的时候，
uh but when it went a skew that I out
嗯，但后来情况发生了变化，我的
earned him by a mile uh you have ego at
收入远远超过了他，嗯，你的自尊心受到了
risk you know really uh very much so
威胁，你知道，真的，非常严重。所以，
absolutely and I married the kind of guy
我嫁给了这样的人。
that was most bulletproof for feeling
最不会因为
ashamed about not earning money he was
没赚到钱而感到羞耻的人是比尔·希金斯。他曾是
an FBI agent he was a top selling agent
联邦调查局特工，年轻时是新泽西州的顶级销售员，
he graduated from Annapolis he was an
毕业于安纳波利斯海军学院，是一位
honored Navy Captain I mean he was
受人尊敬的海军上校。我的意思是，他成就斐然，曾担任
Club in the state of New Jersey
新泽西州共和党俱乐部主席，
everything he did he was accomplished
他所做的一切都很成功。而
all I did was run a business all right
我只不过经营一家公司而已。好吧，
however
然而
all of that stuff is not measured by
所有这些都不能用金钱来衡量。
you know once I was making a lot of
你知道，当我赚了很多
it was hard for Bill it was hard for
比尔就很难了。就像
Bill it was like everybody knew me once
每个人都认识我一样，一旦
I had notoriety you're married to
我有了名气，你娶了
Barbara he stopped being bullied Bill
芭芭拉，他不再受欺负了。
Higgins the FBI agent he stopped being
联邦调查局特工比尔·希金斯，
Bill Higgins the Navy Captain I mean all
海军上校比尔·希金斯，我的意思是，所有
that stuff uh kind of didn't count as
这些成就似乎都不再那么重要了，
much anymore and it should have because
这本该很重要，因为
we're in a New York town where everybody
我们身处纽约，每个人都以
values You by how popular and how much
你的名气和收入来衡量你，
money you make and he was less than me
而他不如我。
but how did he stay with the marriage
但这么多年过去了，他是怎么维持这段婚姻的呢？
because Bill really doesn't have much
因为比尔真的不太看重
value for money he never did it's not
金钱，他从来都不看重，
important to him he's just a nice guy
对他来说金钱并不重要，他只是一个好人。 伙计，
but I had an issue with it yeah I had an
但我对此有点意见，是的，
issue I felt uh not feminine enough when
我感觉自己不够女人味。当
you out earn your husband you don't feel
你收入超过丈夫时，你感觉自己不够
that feminine you feel like the caveman
女人味，感觉自己像个穴居人
instead of cavewoman
而不是穴居女人。
we have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结束语的传统，
podcast yes this question is always left
是的，这个问题总是
by the okay the last guest
由上一位嘉宾留下的。上一位
the last guest left the question for you
嘉宾把问题留给了你：
what did you learn from your greatest
你从最大的失败中学到了什么？
I learned that you get back up and all
我学到的是，你要重新站起来，抓住所有的
the opportunities and getting back up
机会，重新站起来必须
just got to be a habit of getting up you
成为一种习惯。你站起来，
get up and you're going to find some
你会找到一些
[__] that you could do something with
可以利用的东西，
just get up
只要站起来就行了。这
that's a habit you have to make that
是一种习惯，你必须养成这种
habit Barbara thank you my pleasure
习惯。芭芭拉，谢谢你，我的荣幸。谢谢你的
thank you for the inspiration thank you
启发，谢谢
for the humor you're hilarious and
你的幽默。你既搞笑又
Brilliant and equal measure and you're
聪明，两者兼备。
you absolutely are you absolutely are
你绝对是
and you're you're definitely in my top
我最
two favorite sharks you and Damien are
喜欢的两位“鲨鱼”之一，你和达米安是
my favorites so oh forget about Damian
我最喜欢的。哦，算了，达米安
okay he's no good Mark's not good
不行，马克也不行。非常
thank you so much I don't want to be
感谢。我不想成为
among your favorite sharks I want to be
你最喜欢的“鲨鱼”之一，我想成为……
among your favorite people in the world
世界上你最喜欢的人，
you're my favorite shark now now that
你是我最喜欢的鲨鱼，既然
I've mentioned you're so funny but so
提到了你，你真是太有趣了，但真的，真的，
for sure for sure thank you for the
谢谢你的
inspiration I don't believe you I'm
启发，我不相信你，我
looking you in the eyes you can trust me
看着你的眼睛，你可以相信我，
I do trust you you're very trustworthy I
我的确相信你，你非常值得信赖，我
can tell thank you so much Barbara
能感觉到，非常感谢你，芭芭拉。
[Music]
[音乐]
quick word from one of our sponsors I've
来自我们赞助商的一条简短信息：我
got a tip for all of you that will make
有一个小技巧要分享给大家，它会让
your virtual meeting experiences I think
你们的虚拟会议体验
10 times better as some of you may know
提升十倍，你们中的一些人可能已经知道了。Verizon
by now Blue Jeans by Verizon offers
的 Blue Jeans 提供
seamless high quality video conferencing
流畅的高质量视频会议，
but the reason why I use blue jeans
但我使用 Blue Jeans
versus other video conferencing tools is
而不是其他视频会议工具的原因是它的
because of immersion their tools make
沉浸感。他们的工具让
you feel more connected to the employees
你感觉与你想要互动的员工或客户之间联系更紧密。
with and now they're launching one of
现在，他们推出了
impact virtual events so far called Blue
迄今为止对虚拟活动影响最大的功能增强之一，叫做 Blue
Jean Studio I actually used it the other
Jean Studio。前几天我用它
day I did a virtual event using the
做了一个虚拟活动，用
studio which I think about 700 of you
Studio 制作的，我想大概有 700 人参加，
came to TV level production quality all
达到了电视级别的制作质量，所有这些都是
done by one person with very little
一个几乎没有
technical experience on a laptop so if
技术经验的人用笔记本电脑完成的。所以，如果
you've got an event coming up and you're
你有 如果您即将举办活动，并且正在
thinking about doing it virtually check
考虑以线上形式举办，不妨了解
out blue jean studio now let me know
一下 Blue Jean Studio。现在就告诉我
what you think because I genuinely
您的想法，因为我真心认为
believe I know this is an advert and I'm
它是目前为止
believe it's the best tool I've seen for
我见过的最好的工具，能够
doing really immersive simple but high
打造真正沉浸式、简单易用且
quality production virtual events
高质量的线上活动。
[Music]
[音乐]
foreign
外国